[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
COLTON OGDEN: Hello, everybody.
科尔顿·奥格登：大家好
Welcome to GD50 Lecture 2.
欢迎来到GD50第二讲
This is Breakout.
这里是越狱频道
And interestingly, CS50 has a history with Breakout,
有趣的是 CS50与Breakout有渊源
so I pulled this up today.
所以我今天调出了这个
This is Pset3 in 2015, 2014.
这是2015、2014年的Pset3
It was an implementation of Breakout using the Stanford Portable
它是使用斯坦福便携的Breakout的实现
Library, which was a sort of Java library
库 这是一种Java库
that we were able to get C bindings for.
我们能够为其获得C绑定
And so students were able to actually implement
因此 学生们能够实际实施
a game what was at the time the CS50 appliance, which is a Linux distro.
这是一款当时还是CS50设备的游戏 是一个Linux发行版
But suffice to say that was--
但我只想说 那是--
oh, a funny story also.
哦 这也是个有趣的故事
I happened to also write the lasers for this implementation back in the day.
我碰巧也为这个实现编写了激光程序
And I think that was one of the first bits of code
我认为这是最早的代码之一
I got my hands dirty with when working with CS50.
我在使用CS50的时候弄脏了自己的手
So today in the context of Breakout, we'll
所以今天在突破的背景下 我们将
be talking about a few different things that we haven't talked about yet.
谈论一些我们还没有谈论过的不同的事情
Sprite sheets being chief among them most likely.
其中最有可能的是雪碧薄片
At least the most visibly so.
至少最明显的是这样
So sprite sheets are simply a way of taking an image, a large image,
因此 精灵纸只是一种拍摄图像的方式 一张大图像
and rather than splitting it, rather than loading individual images
而不是拆分 而不是加载单独的图像
for all of your different things in the game,
对于你在游戏中的所有不同的东西
whether it's your aliens or your paddles or whatnot, you can put everything
不管是你的外星人还是你的球拍什么的 你可以把所有东西
into one sheet and then just sort of index into that sheet using rectangles,
放入一张表中 然后使用矩形对该表进行索引
quads.
四人组
We'll talk about soon.
我们很快就会谈到
Which will allow you to just draw a subset of that image,
这将允许您只绘制该图像的子集
and therefore condense all of your artwork just into one piece, one file.
并因此将您的所有图稿压缩到一个文件中
We'll be talking a little bit more about procedural generation
我们将更多地讨论程序生成
in the context of Breakout.
在越狱的背景下
And in this case, we'll be laying out all the bricks in the game world
在这种情况下 我们将在游戏世界中铺设所有的砖
procedurally.
从程序上讲
So having instead of the same set of colors, in this case,
因此 在这种情况下 不是使用相同的颜色集
the standard layout is to have a bunch of the same colored bricks row by row.
标准的布局是一排一排地放一堆相同颜色的砖
We'll actually implement a dynamic generation approach
我们实际上将实现一种动态生成方法
and have a bunch of different cool layouts we'll see.
并有一堆不同的酷布局 我们将看到
And it's actually quite simple to achieve pretty believable results.
实际上很容易就能得到可信的结果
We'll manage state a little bit better in this game.
我们会在这场比赛中更好地管理状态
So before we sort of had a couple of global variables
在我们有一些全局变量之前
and we didn't really have the concept of a per state or a global state
我们并没有每个州或全球州的概念
that we were cleanly sort of sharing between all of our states
在我们所有的州之间
for our state machine.
我们的国家机器
But to avoid having sort of like a polluted global name space
但为了避免有一种污染的全球名称空间
and to just sort of keep things a little bit cleaner,
为了让事情变得更干净
we'll end up taking all of the important variables for our code like, you know,
我们最终会把所有重要的变量都作为我们的代码 你知道
the player and any other entities.
玩家和任何其他实体
The bricks, the ball.
砖块球
And rather than keep them in our main [INAUDIBLE],,
而不是让他们在我们的主要[听不见]
we'll end up shifting them.
我们最终会转移他们
We'll sort of transfer them to and from the different states
我们会把他们从不同的州转移到不同的州
via the state machine's enter method.
通过状态机的enter方法
We'll actually have levels.
实际上我们会有水平
So a progression system.
这是一个渐进系统
So start at level one, go up.
从第一层开始 往上走
And then with each level, we'll implement a scale
然后在每一个级别上 我们将实现一个规模
in terms of the generation of the bricks.
在砖块的生成方面
So we'll get higher tiered bricks and more points as a result.
因此 我们将得到更高层次的砖和更多的点作为一个结果
We'll have a health system.
我们会有一个健康系统
So hearts, in a similar fashion to Legend of Zelda.
《心》与《塞尔达传说》相似
Particle systems, which are a very important aesthetic component
粒子系统 这是一个非常重要的美学组成部分
to 2D games and 3D games.
2D游戏和3D游戏
Particle systems basically being a bunch of spawned images
粒子系统基本上是一堆产生的图像
that you sort of cluster, you put into a little spawner,
你可以把它们聚在一起 放进一个小产卵器里
emit them in a certain way, and color them, perform math on them,
以某种方式发射它们 给它们上色 对它们进行数学运算
and get sort of believable effects like fire and smoke
并得到一些可信的效果 比如火和烟
and all these other things that would otherwise
以及所有其他的事情
be not easy to do using simple animation,
使用简单的动画并不容易
but trivial with a particle system.
但对粒子系统来说微不足道
We'll do a little bit more complicated collision detection with our paddle
我们会用球拍做一个更复杂的碰撞检测
and with our bricks than we did with Pong.
比我们和乒乓的关系要好得多
And then we'll also talk lastly about how
最后我们还会讨论
we can save data locally to our computer so that when we close the application
我们可以将数据本地保存到我们的计算机上 这样当我们关闭应用程序时
and run it again, we end up having a persistent high score rather
再运行一次 我们最终得到了一个持续的高分
than just something that's volatile.
而不仅仅是一些不稳定的东西
So first though, I would like to demo today's finished game.
所以首先 我想演示一下今天完成的游戏
So if anybody would like to demo from the audience, that would be nice.
因此 如果有人想从观众那里演示一下 那就太好了
Go ahead and come up.
来吧 上来吧
I'll go ahead and cue it up for you.
我先走一步 为你做好准备
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
JEREMY: Jeremy.
杰里米：杰里米
COLTON OGDEN: Jeremy.
科尔顿·奥格登：杰里米
Colton.
科尔顿
JEREMY: Nice to meet you, Colton.
杰里米：很高兴认识你 科尔顿
COLTON OGDEN: Nice to meet you.
科尔顿·奥格登：很高兴见到你
So we're going to go ahead and run Breakout here.
因此 我们将继续在这里运行Breakout
And so it uses the arrow keys.
所以它使用了箭头键
So if you go ahead and press up and down,
所以如果你继续往上按 然后往下按
you'll see you can move between the start and the high score screen.
你会看到你可以在开始屏幕和高分屏幕之间移动
So they're two separate screens.
所以它们是两个独立的屏幕
So go ahead and--
所以去吧 然后--
here we have when you start, you can choose a paddle.
在我们这里 当你开始的时候 你可以选择一个球拍
So rather than just the same old paddle every time, you get to select.
因此 你可以选择 而不是每次都是同样的老牌球拍
And as you can see here, he chose green.
正如你在这里看到的 他选择了绿色
So he gets the green paddle.
所以他拿到了绿色球拍
These bricks all procedure generated.
这些砖都是程序生成的
So if he runs the application, they'll be completely different.
因此 如果他运行应用程序 它们将完全不同
And as is the classic formula, the ball moves
就像经典的公式一样 球移动
between the bricks and the paddle.
在砖头和球拍之间
When it hits a brick, if it's of a certain color,
当它击中砖块时 如果它是某种颜色的
it'll either get destroyed-- in this case, if it's blue,
它要么被摧毁--在这种情况下 如果它是蓝色的
it's the base color brick.
这是基色砖
So it's the lowest value.
所以这是最低的值
And if it's higher than blue, it'll end up
如果它比蓝色高 它最终会变成
going down a color depending on which color it is.
根据颜色的不同向下调整颜色
I believe it goes blue, green, red, purple, yellow.
我相信它会变成蓝色、绿色、红色、紫色、黄色
So anything higher will get shifted down.
因此 任何更高的东西都会被下移
And then the player amasses points, as you can see top right.
然后玩家积累分数 如你在右上角所看到的
Score.
得分
And notice also the three hearts.
还要注意这三颗心
That will be the player's health.
这将是球员的健康
So if he were to lose on purpose possibly,
所以如果他可能故意输掉比赛
we can see he gets another message that's saying press Enter to serve.
我们可以看到他收到了另一条消息 说按Enter键服务
His hearts have gone down by one.
他的心跳下降了一分
So now he's got two out of three health.
所以现在他有三分之二的健康状况
And so eventually if he were to by chance lose completely--
所以最终 如果他碰巧完全输了--
oh.
噢
That's honestly the most fun part about Breakout
老实说 这是越狱最有趣的部分
is just getting it caught in a bunch of stuff.
只是让它卡在一堆东西里
But you can see we go to a Game Over screen.
但你可以看到我们在屏幕上观看了一场比赛
It shows your final score.
它会显示你的最终分数
And then you can press Enter and it will--
然后你可以按Enter 它就会--
oh.
噢
I must have had a bug.
我一定是染上了虫子
But that should take you back to the--
但这应该会把你带回--
if in the event that you have a high score,
如果你的分数很高
it'll take you to enter a high score.
你要打出一个高分才行
And if you don't have a high score, it'll take you back to the Start menu.
如果你的分数不高 它会把你带回开始菜单
So I made a couple of last minute changes.
所以我在最后一刻做了几处改动
Unfortunately I must have left something in there.
不幸的是 我一定是把什么东西落在里面了
But that's Breakout in a nutshell.
但简而言之 这就是突破
Our goal today will be to implement basically all the functionality we saw.
我们今天的目标是基本实现我们看到的所有功能
Oh, we didn't take a look at the high score screen.
哦 我们没有看高分屏幕
So let's take a look at that really quick as well.
所以让我们也快速地来看看这一点
So here at the title, you can see we have Start and High Scores.
所以在这里的冠军 你可以看到我们有起跑和高分
Oh, man.
哦 伙计
OK.
好的
I must have screwed something up.
我一定是搞砸了什么
So I'm going want to go [INAUDIBLE] Breakout 12.
所以我要去参加[INAUDIBLE]突破12
OK.
好的
Sorry.
抱歉的
I apologize.
我向你道歉
I'm going to fix that.
我会解决这个问题的
But it should show this menu here where you will have a list of all your names
但它应该在这里显示这个菜单 在这里您将有一个包含您所有姓名的列表
that get loaded from a file and will output your score accordingly.
从文件中加载 并相应地输出您的分数
And in the event that you get a new high score,
如果你得到了新的最高分
you'll get to enter your name after that,
在那之后你可以输入你的名字
and then it will end up saving it to another file.
然后 它将最终将其保存到另一个文件
And when we get to that point I'll try and fix it
当我们达到这一点时 我会试着修复它
so that we can actually see what it looks like.
这样我们才能真正看到它的样子
So let's go back to these slides here.
所以让我们回到这些幻灯片上来
So this is the overall state, flow of our game.
这就是我们游戏的整体状态和流程
So as you can see by me marking it out in a highlighted color,
所以你可以看到 我用高亮的颜色把它标出来
we start off in the StartState.
我们从StartState开始
And this is all stuff we've covered before.
这些都是我们以前讲过的内容
Just the state machine.
只有状态机
It's a little bit more complicated than Flappy Bird.
它比Flappy Bird要复杂一点
We have eight states as opposed to I think it
我们有八个州 而不是我认为的
was four or five in the last lecture.
上一节课有四五个人
And the arrows illustrate which states can move in between other states.
箭头显示了哪些状态可以在其他状态之间移动
So as we saw, the StartState can move via the up and down arrows
如我们所见 StartState可以通过向上和向下箭头移动
in the HighScoreState.
在High ScoreState
It can move between the HighScoreState and back.
它可以在HighScoreState和Back之间移动
So when you go into the HighScoreState, press Escape,
所以当你进入HighScoreState时 按Escape键
go back to the StartState.
回到StartState
The StartState also has an arrow branching off
StartState也有一个分支箭头
to the left going down to the PaddleSelectState
向左一直到PaddleSelectState
where we saw the user is able to select a paddle to use.
我们看到用户能够选择要使用的划桨
Once they've selected a paddle, we'll go to the ServeState.
一旦他们选择了划桨 我们就去ServeState
They'll be able to serve the ball at their leisure.
他们将能够悠闲地发球
And then it will go back and forth between the PlayState.
然后它将在PlayState之间来回移动
So if they end up taking damage, the ball
因此 如果他们最终受到损害 球
goes below the surface of the screen, they'll go back to the ServeState
在屏幕表面以下 它们将返回到ServeState
again so they can reorient themselves.
这样他们才能重新定位自己
If they're in the PlayState and they end up scoring,
如果他们在PlayState 他们最终得分
clearing the whole entire set of bricks, they'll
清理整套砖 他们会
actually get taken to the VictoryState.
实际上被带到了维克托州
And the VictoryState is where we increment the level
而VictoryState是我们增加级别的地方
and we also regenerate the level.
我们还重新生成了级别
And the VictoryState goes back to the ServeState,
而VictoryState回到ServeState
and then we repeat that whole loop again.
然后我们再重复一遍整个循环
In the PlayState if they are to get a Game Over,
在PlayState 如果他们想要结束一场比赛
they'll go to the GameOverState, it'll tell them their score,
他们会去GameOverState 它会告诉他们他们的分数
and then they'll go to the EnterHighScoreState
然后他们会进入EnterHighScoreState
depending on whether they have a high score.
取决于他们的分数是否很高
And if not, as seen by the arrow that goes up and to the left,
如果不是 如向上和向左的箭头所示
they'll actually go back to the StartState.
他们实际上会回到星际之州
And then the EnterHighScoreState will also go back to the HighScoreState
然后EnterHighScoreState也将返回到HighScoreState
so that they can see once they've entered
这样他们一进门就能看到
their high score, their score relative to the other scores in the list.
他们的高分 他们的分数相对于列表中的其他分数
So in Breakout0, which we're going to look at now,
所以在我们现在要看的《突破0》中
we're going to do some very basic stuff.
我们要做一些非常基本的事情
So this is the Day 0 update as always.
因此 这是一如既往的第0天更新
I'm in Breakout0 right now.
我现在在《越狱0》里
Yes, I am.
是的 我是
So what we're going to do is we're going to look at first thing here, line 27.
所以我们要做的是 我们首先来看这里的第27行
So before what we were doing in our application
所以在我们在应用程序中所做的事情之前
is having basically a lot of files at the top level and sort of losing track
基本上在顶层有很多文件 有点迷失了方向
of what we were doing potentially.
我们可能在做什么
Especially as you start adding more and more files
特别是当你开始添加越来越多的文件
and you've got like 50, 100 more files, that's
还有50到100个文件
something that's obviously not maintainable.
一些明显不重要的东西
So the solution there, just put them in folders
所以解决的办法是 把它们放在文件夹里
and then keep track of everything.
然后记录所有的事情
Keep them organized.
让他们有组织
And that's a major thing that we're going to start doing.
这是我们要开始做的一件大事
And on top of that, we're also going to, in our code,
最重要的是 在代码中
keep things a little bit more modular.
让事情变得更加模块化
And that's why we have this file source slash dependencies,
这就是为什么我们有这个文件源斜杠依赖项
which we'll take a look at in a second.
我们马上就会看到
We've allocated a bunch of global tables here.
我们在这里分配了一堆全局表
So we're taking the design decision of even
所以我们的设计决定
though I mentioned that we will be sort of taking a lot of the global variables
虽然我提到过我们会把很多全局变量
out of our application assets, we're going to keep
从我们的应用程序资产中
all of those in some global variables.
所有这些都是全局变量
And we'll see in the future how we can maybe implement a resource manager
将来我们会看到如何实现资源管理器
class that takes care of this for us.
为我们解决这个问题
But for now, for simplicity's sake, in love.load,
但现在 为了简单起见 在爱 负荷
we're just going to have a few global tables that contain,
我们只需要几个全局表
in this case, global fonts.
在本例中是全局字体
So by key, we can index small, medium, and large fonts,
通过键 我们可以索引小 中 大字体
which are just new fonts at different sizes.
就是不同大小的新字体
8, 16, 32.
八十六三十二
And we're using it.
我们正在利用它
We have a fonts folder now instead of just keeping it at the parent level.
我们现在有一个字体文件夹 而不仅仅是保持在父级
We're going to set it to small.
我们将把它设置为小
We have global textures.
我们有全局纹理
So background, main, arrows, hearts, particle.
背景 主 箭头 红心 粒子
So we have the background, which was the background of our screen.
所以我们有背景 这是我们屏幕的背景
Main has all of our bricks, paddles, the balls, et cetera.
我们所有的砖块球拍球等等都在总部
Arrows are going to be for the paddle select screen.
箭头将用于桨选择屏幕
The two left and right arrows.
两个左右箭头
Hearts are going to be for our health.
心脏是为了我们的健康
And then particle is a single, small, tiny little texture
粒子是一个很小很小的纹理
that we'll use to spawn all the particles in our particle systems
我们将用它来产生粒子系统中的所有粒子
later on as we get towards the end of the demonstration.
稍后当我们接近演示的尾声时
So this is push.
所以这是推
We're setting it up just like normal.
我们就像平常一样布置
Nothing new there.
没什么新鲜的
Except the virtual width, virtual height, and all that stuff,
除了虚拟宽度 虚拟高度 以及所有这些东西
those have been moved out, if we look into source in a constants file.
如果我们在一个常量文件中查看源代码 这些都被移走了
So this file here, instead of having all the constants in main,
所以这个文件 没有包含main中的所有常量
it kind of makes sense just to take them out, put them
把它们拿出来
in a file called constants.lua, and we can sort manage all that.
在一个名为constants.lua的文件中 我们可以排序管理所有这些
We can know immediately when we're looking at capital window
当我们看到资本窗口时
width, window height, et cetera.
宽度 窗户高度 等等
And these are all constants.
这些都是常量
If you have a constants file, we just can more easily
如果你有一个常量文件 我们可以更容易地
track it rather than having to grab through all of our files
追踪它而不是抓取我们所有的文件
to try and figure out what we were looking at.
试图弄清楚我们在看什么
And the constants are used here in our set up screen as before.
和前面一样 常量在设置屏幕中使用
And then another sounds global table, just as before.
然后另一个声音全局表 就像以前一样
We have a bunch of different sound effects.
我们有很多不同的音效
I've separated the music from the sound effects
我把音乐和音效分开了
just so that we can see at a glance, oh, this is the music,
就为了让我们一眼就能看出来 哦 这是音乐
these are the sound effects.
这些是音效
Pretty straight forward.
很直接
We have a state machine, as always.
我们有一个国家机器 一如既往
And we're just going to use a StartState for this demonstration.
我们将使用StartState来进行演示
Setting it to Start.
将其设置为开始
Love.resize, love.update.
爱 调整大小 爱 更新
These are all functions we've seen before.
这些都是我们以前见过的函数
Nothing too new.
没什么新鲜的
Love.keypress.
Love.keypress.
We have a global input table.
我们有一个全局输入表
So as in the case of Flappy Bird, we can index into that input table anywhere
就像Flappy Bird一样 我们可以在任何地方索引输入表
in our application and call love.keyboard.wasPressed[key],
在我们的应用程序中调用love.keyboard.wasPressed[key]
which allows us to take input exclusively from main and use it
它允许我们专门从main获取输入并使用它
in other modules.
在其他模块中
Here we're drawing the--
这里我们画的是
so this is the actual rendering code.
这是实际的渲染代码
And we're doing this in our love.draw as opposed to a specific state
我们在我们的爱中这样做 draw与特定的状态相对
because this is actually going to apply to all states.
因为这实际上适用于所有州
We're always going to have this background.
我们总是会有这样的背景
So rather than duplicate it over and over again,
所以与其一遍又一遍地重复
in this instance, this minor bit of code,
在本例中 这一小段代码
we're going to display the background behind all the states.
我们将显示所有状态后面的背景
So all the states are going to render over this background
所以所有的州都将在这个背景下渲染
and make it seem a little more cohesive.
让它看起来更有凝聚力
We're going to draw at 0, 0 without rotation.
我们将在没有旋转的情况下画0 0
And then this bit of math here, the virtual width
然后这里有一些数学运算 即虚拟宽度
divided by, and then background width minus one, end up being a scale factor
除以 然后背景宽度减去1 最终得到一个比例因子
so that we can always scale it to be our virtual width.
这样我们就可以始终将其调整到我们的虚拟宽度
Because the texture by default is some amount smaller than our actual window
因为默认情况下纹理比实际窗口小一些
or our actual virtual width and height, but by dividing virtual width
或者我们的实际虚拟宽度和高度 但通过除以虚拟宽度
by whatever the background width of that image is by one,
无论该图像的背景宽度是多少
we'll get a scale factor because virtual width is larger than the image.
我们将获得比例因子 因为虚拟宽度大于图像
We'll get a scale factor on X and Y that equates to it completely stretching
我们将得到X和Y的比例因子 它等同于它完全拉伸
to fill our virtual width and height.
来填满我们的虚拟宽度和高度
And recall that these two parameters are the scale on the X and the Y.
回想一下 这两个参数是X和Y上的比例
So it's going to be some, like, one point something or two point something.
所以这将是一些 就像 一点什么或两点什么
Whatever it takes to end up filling the screen.
不惜一切代价来填满屏幕
And then lastly here, the new bit I implemented
最后 在这里 我实现的新Bit
is just a display of frames per second function, which I think
只是一个每秒显示帧的函数 我认为
is kind of important generally, and it's very easy to do.
通常是很重要的 而且很容易做到
I don't recall, I don't think we talked about it yet, but just
我不记得了 我想我们还没谈过 但只是
love.timer.getFPS.
Love.timer.getFPS
And then I just draw in the top left in green
然后我就在左上角画上绿色
so that we can see it throughout all of our iterations of the game, what
这样我们就可以在游戏的所有迭代中看到它 什么
are frames per second are.
每秒的帧数是
If you want to monitor without having to look through your terminal or anything
如果您想要在无需查看终端或任何东西的情况下进行监控
like that, just displaying at the top, it's
就像这样 就在上面显示 它是
standard practice in a lot of games.
这是很多比赛中的标准练习
If you've gone to the debug console or whatnot
如果您已进入调试控制台或诸如此类的
or sort of looked into some of the hacks,
或者是调查了一些黑客行为
you'll see that in a lot of places.
你会在很多地方看到这一点
So I talked earlier about dependencies.lua.
所以我早些时候谈到了依赖
So this ties in as well to our effort to sort of modularize everything,
因此 这也与我们将一切模块化的努力联系在一起
keep everything organized.
保持一切井然有序
Instead of requiring everything at the top of main,
而不是要求所有东西都放在Main的顶部
let's just put it all in a file and then we'll
让我们把它们都放在一个文件里 然后我们
know at a glance what we're requiring and we don't have to look through main
一目了然地知道我们需要什么 我们不必查看Main
and make main 100 lines, potentially a lot more than it needs to be.
并建造100条主线 这可能比需要的要多得多
So requiring push, requiring class.
所以需要推动 需要上进
Same as we've done before.
和我们以前做的一样
Require source.constants.
需要Soure.Constants
We have access to those.
我们有权访问这些文件
Require StateMachine, and then BaseState and StartState.
需要StateMachine 然后是BaseState和StartState
So let's go ahead and take a look at our StartState.
那么 让我们继续来看看我们的StartState
So I put states in a subfolder of source.
所以我把州放在了SOURCE的子文件夹中
This is another effort to sort of keep things modular.
这是另一种让事情保持模块化的努力
In this particular project, we won't have a lot of nested folders of code,
在这个特定的项目中 我们不会有很多嵌套的代码文件夹
but I decided to put the states in their own folder
但我决定把各州放在他们自己的文件夹里
just so easily you can get access to all your states.
你可以很容易地访问你所有的州
So we'll look at StartState here on line 21.
因此 我们将在这里的第21行查看StartState
So recall in the StartState, we just had Breakout in the center of the screen
回想一下 在StartState中 我们刚刚在屏幕中央显示了Breakout
and then we had Start Game and High Scores.
然后我们有了首发比赛和高分
So the user was able to highlight which state he wanted to look at.
因此 用户能够突出显示他想要查看的州
So we need to keep track of which one is highlighted.
因此 我们需要跟踪突出显示的是哪一个
So all this variable's purpose is just to keep track.
所以所有这个变量的目的只是为了跟踪
So one or two.
那就一两个吧
One being Play Game, and two being High Scores.
一个是玩游戏 两个是高分
And then here if we press up and down, then we--
然后在这里 如果我们上下按压 那么我们--
because there's only two options effectively,
因为实际上只有两种选择
you can just flip whatever highlight is with one or two.
你可以只用一两个来翻转任何高亮的部分
If you have a list of options that's more than two,
如果你有一个多于两个的选项列表
you'll need to increment one until it gets to whatever
你需要递增一个 直到它到达任何
X is, your number of list options.
X是您的列表选项的数量
And then if you press down at that point,
然后如果你在那个点按下
you should flip back up to the top.
你应该翻到最上面去
And the same holds true for whether you're at option one.
同样的道理也适用于你是否选择了第一种选择
You should go flip, rotate to the bottom of your list
你应该去翻转 旋转到你的清单的底部
so that it looks as if you've gone all the way around.
这样看起来你就像是绕了一圈
And-- then we're just playing a sound here when we do that.
然后--当我们这样做的时候 我们只是在这里播放声音
We have a love.keyboard.wasPressed[escape] call
我们有一个love.keyboard.wa按下[退出]调用
here.
这里
It's not global anymore because there are some states in our application
它不再是全局的 因为我们的应用程序中有一些状态
where we might want to press Escape to actually go backwards,
我们可能想按下Escape来后退
and we'll see that.
我们会看到的
And so rendering here.
在这里渲染
We render Breakout with a large font.
我们用大字体渲染Breakout
Now that we can access G fonts at large key in the center of the screen,
现在我们可以在屏幕中央的大键处访问G字体
set medium font.
设置中等字体
And then we're going to render our two text fields one after the other.
然后我们将一个接一个地呈现两个文本字段
But if highlighted is equal to one, then we're
但如果高亮部分等于1
going to set it to some blue color, which is one of three--
将它设置为蓝色 这是三种颜色之一
255, 255, 255.
255 255 255
And then render it.
然后将其渲染
And then make sure to reset the color after that because recall
然后确保在那之后重置颜色 因为回想一下
love 2D is sort of like a state machine in its own right,
爱情2D本身就像一个状态机
where if you set the color to something, whatever you draw and render
如果你给某个东西设置颜色 不管你画什么
after that, be it images or text, will adopt that color.
然后呢 不管是图片还是文字 都会采用这个颜色
So having everything be 255, 255, 255, 255,
所有的都是255 255 255 255
which is pure white, completely opaque, has
它是纯白色的 完全不透明
the effect of drawing everything completely opaque.
把所有东西都画成完全不透明的效果
But if you don't do that, your images or whatnot that you draw afterwards
但如果你不这样做 你的图像或你后来画的东西
will be tinted or transparent, which you most of the time don't want.
会是有色的或透明的 这是你大多数时候不想要的
But you might sometimes want that, and we'll actually
但有时候你可能会想要
see that in the PaddleSelectState.
在PaddleSelectState中可以看到
And same thing holds true here.
同样的道理也适用于这里
If highlighted is two, do the exact same thing.
如果突出显示的是两个 则执行完全相同的操作
And so if we run this application, which is mainly
如果我们运行这个应用程序
just a subset of what we saw before, we can move up and down
只是我们之前看到的一个子集 我们可以上下移动
between Start and High Scores.
在开始和最高分之间
But if we press Enter on any of them, nothing
但如果我们按下任何一个回车键
happens because we have no event handlers actually taking care of that.
因为我们没有事件处理程序来处理它
But we have the image scaled to the screen, we have Breakout in the middle,
但是我们有缩放到屏幕上的图像 我们有中间的突破
and we have our two menu options there.
我们有两个菜单选项
So Breakout1.
所以Breakout 1.
So this is where we start to dive a little bit into sprite sheets, which
这就是我们开始深入精灵表的地方
is a major component of game development, 2D game
是游戏开发的主要组成部分 2D游戏
development that we'll be looking at in the future and in this application.
我们将在未来和这个应用程序中看到的发展
But a sprite sheet is just, ultimately, rather than have--
但最终 精灵表单只是 而不是有--
I don't know how many images there are on this sprite sheet here.
我不知道这张精灵纸上有多少张图片
But however many of these files, just have
但无论这些文件有多少 只要有
one file put them all together, and then using rectangles, define
一个文件将它们放在一起 然后使用矩形定义
where all the different sprites are.
所有不同的精灵都在那里
And then when we want to draw, use those rectangles
然后当我们想要画的时候 使用这些矩形
and just tell love.graphics.draw, I want you
告诉我爱 图解 画 我要你
to draw this texture, this sprite sheet, but I want
来绘制这个纹理 这个精灵图案 但是我想
you to draw just this section of it.
你只需要画它的这一部分.
You'd pass it in a quad, which is just simply rectangle with height, X and Y.
你会在一个四边形中传递它 这个四边形只是一个简单的矩形 上面有高度 X和Y
And love 2D will know, OK, I'm going to draw the image, but only this bit.
喜欢2D的人会知道 好的 我要画这个图像 但只有这一点
And it has the effect of looking as if you're only drawing tiny little images
它的效果就像你只画了很小的图像
as opposed to one monstrous image.
而不是一个可怕的形象
And the functions that are relevant for us to look at
以及与我们要查看的相关函数
are love.graphics.newquad, which takes an X, Y, width, and a height.
是love.graph ics.newquad 它接受X、Y、宽度和高度
And also a dimensions object, which you get from an image.
还有一个维度对象 这是从图像中获得的
We'll see that.
我们会看到的
And all that basically is, I believe, is just an X, Y, width and height as well.
我相信 所有这些基本上只是一个X Y 宽度和高度
Or just a width and a height, rather, from whatever image
或者只是宽度和高度 更确切地说 来自任何图像
you want to create quads for.
您想要为创建四边形
And then love.graphics.draw, we've already seen it,
然后是爱 画 画 我们已经看过了
but this is a different signature.
但这是一个不同的签名
This has texture, quad, X, Y. Quad being the second argument.
这有纹理 四边形 X Y 四边形是第二个参数
And when it takes in this quad, it knows to only draw
当它进入这个四边形时 它知道只有抽签
that defined rectangle of image to the screen.
定义的矩形图像显示在屏幕上
And so we'll go ahead and take a look now at Breakout1.
接下来 我们将继续关注《突破1》
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: The question was, are there any tools
科尔顿·奥格登：问题是 有没有什么工具
so that we don't have to guess where the quad is when we're doing the sheet?
这样我们在做床单的时候就不用去猜四合院在哪里了？
Yes, there are a lot of the time.
是的 有很多时间
I looked and saw a couple, but I haven't tested them thoroughly myself.
我看了看 看到了几个 但我自己还没有彻底测试过它们
For simpler examples like this, it's usually
对于像这样的简单示例 通常是
easy enough to programmatically do it.
非常简单 可以通过编程来完成
But yeah, when you get into having giant sprite atlases where
但是的 当你开始阅读巨型精灵地图集时
you have especially things that are not necessarily symmetrical
你有特别的东西不一定是对称的
or rectangular looking even though they still need to be defined rectangularly,
或者看起来是矩形的 尽管它们仍然需要被限定为矩形
it's often best to use a tool like that.
通常最好使用这样的工具
There are, I do believe, I just haven't used them.
有 我相信 我只是没有使用它们
I can bring it up in a future lecture so we can discuss.
我可以在以后的讲座中提出来 这样我们就可以讨论了
Any other questions before we carry into Breakout1?
在我们进入Breakout 1之前还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好吧
So I'm going to go ahead and open up the very first thing
所以我将打开第一个
we should look at on Breakout1.
我们应该在Breakout 1上看看
In the source directory, we have a new file.
在源目录中 我们有一个新文件
And from here on out, I'm going to assume,
从现在开始 我假设
we're going to always assume that when we introduce a new file,
我们总是假设当我们引入一个新文件时
we're going to include it in dependencies.lua.
我们将把它包含在dependencies. lua中
And so in this case, all we need to do is just say require source/util.
所以在这种情况下 我们只需要说require source/util
And as you can see, we're also adding a PlayState to this demonstration.
正如你所看到的 我们还在这个演示中添加了一个PlayState
But from here on out, I won't make mention of us actually
但从现在开始 我不会再提我们了
adding it to our project.
将其添加到我们的项目中
So util.lua is the module that contains the code
所以util.lua是包含代码的模块
we're going to use to actually generate quads for a given sprite sheet.
我们将使用它来为给定的精灵表生成四边形
And this function, all it does, is it takes an atlas or sprite sheet--
这个函数 它所做的就是 它需要一个地图集或精灵表--
the names are synonymous.
这两个名字是同义的
You'll hear them both.
你会听到他们两个
Or we pass it an Atlas, we pass it the width of the tile that we want
或者我们给它一个地图集 我们给它我们想要的瓷砖的宽度
and the height of the tile that we want.
和瓷砖的高度
It's going to get the width and the height of the sheet here.
它会得到纸张的宽度和高度
So every image has a function called get width and get height,
所以每幅图像都有一个函数叫做获取宽度和高度
so we're just going to do that.
所以我们就这么做
And specifically the sheet width and sheet height
特别是纸张的宽度和高度
are the width of the image divided by tile width and tile height.
是图像的宽度除以图块宽度和图块高度
So we know how many times we need to iterate over the sprite sheet
这样我们就知道我们需要在精灵表上重复多少次
to generate a rectangle.
来生成矩形
We're dividing it up based on the size of our tiles.
我们根据瓷砖的大小来划分
And then we just basically do a simple nested four loop here.
然后我们在这里做一个简单的嵌套四个循环
We start a counter and a sprite sheet.
我们开始一个计数器和一个精灵表
This sprite sheet is going to be a table that holds all of our quads.
这个精灵表将是一个表 容纳我们所有的四边形
We just say for Y, get zero.
我们只说Y 得到零
Sheet height minus one.
图纸高度减一
So starting at the top left, going down.
所以从左上角开始往下走
And starting at the top going down, and then x equals zero,
从顶部开始向下 然后x等于零
starting at the left going right.
从左边开始向右转
At sprite sheet, sheet counter, which is one here because in lua,
在Sprite Sheet Sheet Counter 这是一个因为在Lua
tables are one indexed.
表是一个索引表
We're going to create a new quad at X times tile width, Y times tile width.
我们将创建一个新的四边形 X乘以瓷砖宽度 Y乘以瓷砖宽度
Give it the width and the height of our tile.
给它和我们的瓷砖一样的宽度和高度
So just whatever we passed into our function signature.
所以 无论我们传递给函数签名的是什么
Here it will often be in this case be 16 by 32
在这种情况下 通常是16x32
because that's the size of the bricks.
因为这就是砖块的大小
And then we pass in the last parameter that we saw in the slide,
然后我们传入幻灯片中看到的最后一个参数
which is atlas:getdimensions.
这就是地图集：获取维度
And then we just increment our sheet counter here.
然后我们只需在这里增加我们的床单计数器
And then at the end of this, when we're all done, we'll return this.
然后在这个结束的时候 当我们都做完了 我们会把这个还回去
We'll have a table of quads that we can then
我们会有一张四合院的桌子 然后我们就可以
use that are in a sort of one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
以一、二、三、四、五、六、七、八的形式使用
Well, I should say, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight top
嗯 我应该说 一 二 三 四 五 六 七 八
left to bottom right of all the sprites in our sheet to make it
从左到右是我们床单上所有的精灵
super easy to look at.
看起来超级简单
We have another function here.
我们这里还有一个功能
Lua doesn't by default, have a slice function, but we are just adding to it.
默认情况下 Lua没有切片功能 但我们只是在添加它
Table.slice.
桌子 切片
It takes the table a first, the first entry in the table that we want,
它首先获取表 表中我们想要的第一个条目
the last entry, and then the step between them.
最后一个条目 然后是它们之间的步骤
Just like Pythons slice function, it just iterates over the
就像Pythons切片函数一样 它只是迭代
for loop, which is first till one.
For循环 这是倒数第一个循环
So one by default. Until the last or until whatever this sort of number sign
因此 默认情况下只有一个 直到最后或者直到任何这样的数字符号
is the size of a table, which I don't think we've introduced yet.
是一张桌子的大小 我想我们还没有介绍过
But basically, if we pass in last, it'll stop there, otherwise just
但基本上 如果我们最后通过 它就会止步于此 否则
assume we want the whole entire table.
假设我们想要整个表
And then this comma here at the end, which has step or one,
然后这个逗号在末尾 它有一步或一步
you can pass in a step at the end of a for loop as a third argument,
您可以在for循环的末尾传入一个步骤作为第三个参数
and that will be however much increments or decrements the loop that you're in.
这将会增加或减少你所处的循环
So by default, just one.
因此 默认情况下 只有一个
We go one, then we go to two, then we go to three.
我们先走一步 然后走到第二步 再走到第三步
But you can set it to negative one.
但您可以将其设置为负1
And so if you say four i gets three to one minus one,
所以如果你说四 我得到三减一
you'll go three, two, one.
你来三 二 一
And you can't do normally a step, which is what we do here.
而且你不能正常地走一步 而我们这里就是这样做的
No, you can do a step, but you can't slice,
不 你可以走一步 但你不能切开
which is why we have here sliced at number of slice plus one gets table i,
这就是为什么我们在这里以切片的数量加一得到表i
and then eventually we return slice.
然后最终我们返回Slice
So it just returns just a segment of whatever table we're in.
所以它只返回我们所在表的一部分
And then the important function here that we're actually
然后这里的重要功能是 我们实际上
going to use in our application, we're going to generate quads paddles.
要在我们的应用程序中使用 我们将生成四足桨
And so this takes X and Y, 0 and 64.
所以这需要X和Y 0和64
And if we look back at our paddles here, we
如果我们回过头来看我们的桨 我们
can see that we have various different sizes.
可以看到我们有各种不同的尺码
So we have a small one, a medium one, a large one, and then a really large one.
所以我们有一个小的 一个中号的 一个大的 然后是一个非常大的
So if we want to get every single paddle in our sprite sheet,
所以如果我们想把每一只桨都放在雪碧表上
small, medium, large, giant, notice that we have four blocks
小、中、大、大 请注意 我们有四个街区
and within each of those blocks we have four different sizes.
在每一块中 我们有四种不同的大小
So we can just iterate over this four times
所以我们可以重复这四次
and then just define whatever the size of this rect
然后定义这个矩形的大小
is, that rect, that rect, and that rect.
就是那个教区 那个教区 那个教区
And we'll see the math for it here.
我们将在这里看到它的数学计算
If I go zero to three, for i, get zero till three.
如果我从零到三 对我来说 从零到三
We're going to go ahead because that will give us four.
我们要继续 因为这会给我们四个
So that's how many times we want to iterate over the sprite sheet
这就是我们要在精灵工作表上迭代的次数
to get the separate quads.
才能得到单独的四元组
We'll get the smallest one.
我们会买最小的
So quads counter.
因此 四元组起了反作用
We initialize counter to one.
我们将计数器初始化为1
Gets love.graphics, that new quad at X, Y, with the 32 and 16.
得到了爱 图形 这个新的四边形在X Y 32和16
Oh, and X and Y default at 0 and 64 here because the note--
哦 X和Y在这里默认为0和64 因为音符--
recall that these are all 16 tall here.
回想一下 这里的这些都是16个高的
So we're starting Y at 64 so that we start right here.
所以我们从64开始 所以我们从这里开始
And we're starting X at zero because it's on the left side.
我们从零开始 因为它在左边
So we'll do that.
所以我们就这么做
We'll increment counter.
我们会递增计数器
Get it at 32 wide by 16 tall.
把它调到32宽16高
Those are the actual dimensions of the smallest one.
这些是最小的一个的实际尺寸
The same exact logic applies for medium and for large.
同样的逻辑也适用于中型和大型企业
Only that we're adding 32 and then we're making it size 64,
只是我们加了32 然后我们把它改成64号
and then we're adding 96 to X at size 96 because they're getting wider,
然后我们在96号的X上加96 因为它们变宽了
but they're also offsetting more to the right.
但他们也在更多地向右倾斜
And then the last bit is pretty much the same thing as before, except now we're
最后一点和以前几乎一样 除了现在我们
going Y plus 16 back to X because we've gone down a row in our sprite sheet
将Y加16返回到X 因为我们在精灵工作表中排到了下一行
The paddle width at that point is 128, but still 16 pixels.
此时的桨宽为128 但仍为16像素
And then here at the bottom because we want to do this four times,
然后在底部 因为我们想要做四次
we want to go through the chunks are effectively 32 pixels
我们想要检查的块实际上是32个像素
because we're going 16, 16, 16, 16.
因为我们要开到16 16 16 16
We're going to add 32 to Y and then go to the next set of four paddles.
我们要把32加到Y上 然后转到下一组四个球拍
So this is how we're effectively getting all of the paddle sprites,
这就是我们如何有效地获得所有的划桨精灵
and they;re going to be stored one through X where I believe X is 16.
它们将从一个存储到X 我相信X是16
So we'll have 16 quads defined in our sprite sheet
因此 我们将在精灵工作表中定义16个四边形
thereafter that we can then return.
之后 我们就可以回来了
So I'm going to go back to main.lua now on line 64.
所以我要回到主要的 Lua 现在在64行
Here we have a new global table called gframes.
这里我们有一个新的全局表 名为GFRAMES
We'll be able to access this anywhere we want to draw stuff.
我们将能够在任何想要画东西的地方访问它
And it's just the same thing that we just saw.
这和我们刚刚看到的是一样的
Generate quads paddles, and we just pass it in our main texture.
生成四足桨 我们只是在我们的主纹理中传递它
And our main texture is this.
我们的主要质地是这个
This is what our main texture looks like.
这是我们的主要纹理看起来是什么样子
And then we're going to index it.
然后我们要将其编入索引
We're going to say it gets the key paddles,
我们会说它得到了关键的控制板
because in that particular table was just the quads for our paddles.
因为在那个特定的桌子上只有我们的球拍的四个方格
So in the future, we just need to call love.graphics.drawtexture and then
因此 在将来 我们只需要调用love.graph ics.Drawing纹理 然后
index into gframes paddles at whatever paddle we want.
索引到框架划桨在任何我们想要的划桨
And that's how we can keep track of what we want to draw paddle wise.
这就是我们可以跟踪我们想要画的划桨明智的方式
And in this particular demo we have a new paddle class
在这个特定的演示中 我们有一个新的Padle类
because paddle is a thing in our game.
因为划桨是我们比赛中的一件事
We can represent it as sort of a class or an object.
我们可以将其表示为某种类或对象
So we'll define a class for it.
所以我们将为它定义一个类
Everything is pretty simple thus far.
到目前为止 一切都很简单
Gets an X and a Y. Dx is zero with height.
得到X和Y Dx随高度为零
Skin.
皮肤
The skin is going to be what color it is.
皮肤将是什么颜色的
We need to keep track of that.
我们需要跟踪这一点
And then the size, because size will be how we sort of offset
然后是大小 因为大小将是我们排序的偏移量
into our paddles, our quads, because the sizes are small, medium, large, giant.
进入我们的桨 我们的四肢 因为大小有小的 中等的 大的 巨大的
One, two, three, four times four.
一 二 三 四乘四
So one, two, three, four for the first set and then five,
所以第一盘一 二 三 四 然后五
six, seven, eight for the second set.
第二盘是六、七、八
Those are all sort of by color.
这些都是按颜色排列的
So we can just multiply skin times--
所以我们可以乘以皮肤时间--
or we can multiply whatever our size is by skin
或者我们可以通过皮肤来繁殖我们的体型
and that will give us the current frame, the current quad that we want in order
这将为我们提供当前帧 即我们想要的当前四边形
to draw to the screen.
画到屏幕上
And then on line seven--
然后在7号线上--
so this is keyboard input here.
这就是键盘输入
Stuff that we've seen before.
我们以前见过的东西
If we're pressing left or right, then the paddles should move.
如果我们按向左或向右 那么球拍应该会移动
Dx should be set left or right.
DX应设置为左侧或右侧
We want to clamp it.
我们想把它夹住
We saw this, we've seen this as well.
我们看到了这个 我们也看到了这个
Clamp the input to the left and the right side of the screen.
将输入夹在屏幕的左侧和右侧
If the dx is less than zero, do math.max and math.min otherwise
如果dx小于零 则执行math.max和math.min 否则
if we're moving to the right.
如果我们要向右移动
And then here, this is actually where we tie it all together
然后在这里 这实际上是我们将所有东西联系在一起的地方
and we actually use the quads to draw something onto the screen.
我们实际上使用四元组来在屏幕上绘制一些东西
So we're calling love.graphics.draw just our texture, our main texture.
因此 我们将其命名为love.graph 只绘制我们的纹理 我们的主要纹理
And then gframes at paddles at our current size, which is two.
然后在我们现在的大小 也就是两个人的球拍上画出格框
We want to by default have the medium size plus four times whatever
默认情况下 我们想要中号外加四倍的
our skin is, minus one.
我们的皮肤是负一
So if our skin is one, which is the blue skin, we won't add anything to it.
因此 如果我们的皮肤是蓝色皮肤 我们不会向它添加任何东西
It'll just be four times zero.
只会是零的四倍
But if we have the next one, it'll be two minus one,
但如果我们有下一个 就会是二减一
so we'll end up adding four to that.
所以我们最终会在上面加4
And because we're adding four to it times whatever that skin is,
因为无论皮肤是什么 我们都要加四倍
it will just basically put us four quads in,
它基本上会把我们四个四边形放进去
which is the next, the exact same paddle, but the next color.
哪一个是下一个 完全一样的球拍 但下一个颜色
And then lastly what we'll look at here is the PlayState.
最后 我们要看的是PlayState
So we had just the StartState before, but now we
所以我们之前只有StartState 但是现在我们
want to actually test to make sure we can draw a paddle,
我想测试一下 确保我们能画出一个桨
move it around the screen.
在屏幕上移动
So we're going to implement a simple PlayState here.
所以我们要在这里实现一个简单的PlayState
So on line 20, we're just calling self.paddle gets paddle.
所以在第20行 我们只是打电话给self 桨得到桨
We're initializing a new paddle object.
我们正在初始化一个新的paddle对象
And then we're keeping track of also this
然后我们也在跟踪这个
is a simple, like, pause demonstration.
就是一个简单的暂停演示
If self.paused, then-- actually yeah.
如果赛尔夫停顿了一下 那么--事实上是的
Did I say self.paused?
我说了自我停顿吗？
I did.
是的
OK.
好的.
I just don't initialize it to anything.
我只是没有初始化它
I should have set self.paused to false here.
我应该在这里把自己设为假的
If self.paused, we're going to test to see whether we're pressing space,
如果self.暂停了 我们将测试是否按下了空格
and if we are, unpause it.
如果是的话就取消暂停
Otherwise, basically just do the same exact thing in reverse.
否则 基本上只是做同样的事情反过来
If we press space, pause the game, play a sound, et cetera.
如果我们按空格键 暂停游戏 播放声音 等等
Here on line 39, we're just going to call update on the paddle.
在第39行 我们将调用桨的更新
Which, just remember, test for left or right input.
记住 测试左输入还是右输入
Here we want to be able to escape the game,
在这里我们希望能够逃离游戏
so we're going to have a handler for escape.
所以我们会有一个负责逃跑的人
Render the paddle on lines 47, which will do the love.graphics.draw
渲染第47行的桨 这将做爱 图形 绘制
with a quad as we saw before, but it'll use
和我们之前看到的一样 但它会使用
the skin and the size of that paddle to index into the quads tile sheet
皮肤和桨大小以索引到四边形瓦片片中
appropriately.
适当地
And then here if we're paused, let's just draw
然后这里如果我们暂停了 我们就画
some text in the middle of the screen that just says Pause.
屏幕中间的一些文字写着“你好”
And we use the large font.
我们用大号字体
So we can go ahead and demo this now and see everything come together.
所以我们现在可以继续演示 看看所有的东西都在一起
We have as before our StartState.
我们像以前一样有我们的StartState
But if we press Enter, now we go to our PlayState
但是如果我们按下Enter键
and we just have a paddle at the bottom of the screen.
我们在屏幕底部有一个桨
It's size two, skin one.
是2号 1号皮
Just the blue skin.
只有蓝色的皮肤
And we can move it left or right like that.
我们可以像这样左右移动
And if it hits the left side of the screen, it will stop.
如果它击中屏幕的左侧 它会停止
And if it hits the right side of the screen, it will stop as well.
如果它击中屏幕的右侧 它也会停止
So we've made progress, but this is one of the fundamental things
所以我们已经取得了进展 但这是最基本的事情之一
I'd like to showcase today is just, like, using quads and categorizing
我今天要展示的是 就像 使用四元组和分类
them, organizing them, and being able to draw
他们 组织他们 并能够画出
your assets from a large compiled image rather than keep track
您的资产来自一个大的汇编图像 而不是跟踪
of however many images it would take.
不管它拍下多少张照片
And you have to name all of them and sort them.
你必须将它们全部命名并进行分类
It would just be a big pain.
这只会是一种巨大的痛苦
So yeah.
所以是的
Definitely going forward when you have more than one sprite,
当你有不止一个精灵的时候 肯定会继续前进
you want to sort of put it together in one sheet,
你想把它放在一张纸上
and that's how we can accomplish that.
这就是我们实现这一目标的方法
But we don't have bricks, and this is probably
但我们没有砖头 这很可能是
the other big main component of Breakout besides the paddle and the ball.
除了球拍和球之外 突破的另一个主要组成部分
We want to have bricks that we can actually hit and aim for on the screen.
我们想要的是我们可以在屏幕上真正击中和瞄准的砖块
So this update will address that.
因此 此次更新将解决这一问题
So let's go ahead and take a look at Breakout2 in main.lua.
那么让我们继续来看看Breakout2 in Main.Lua
I'm going to open it up here.
我要在这里把它打开
On line 66, you can see we have a new table in our gframes.
在第66行 您可以看到在我们的GFrame中有一个新的表
Because we had one just for paddles, we took out
因为我们有一个专门用来划桨的 所以我们就拿出来了
just the paddles from our sprite sheet.
只有我们精灵床单上的球拍
We're going to do the same thing for just the balls.
我们将对蛋蛋做同样的事情
So we're going to look at-- if we look here,
所以我们要看--如果我们看这里
we can see that the balls sort of come after all of the bricks here
我们可以看到 球是在这里的所有砖块之后出现的
and they're just laid out in eight pixels wide by eight
它们只是以八个像素宽乘八个像素来布置
pixels tall increments here.
像素高的增量在这里
So four pixels to one brick, four balls to one brick,
所以四个像素对应一块砖 四个球对应一块砖
two balls to one horizontally, and then two balls vertically.
两个球水平对一 然后垂直两个球
And so what we'll end up doing is just a simple function in our util
因此 我们最终要做的只是我们的实用程序中的一个简单函数
that takes a look at that.
我们来看看这一点
So let's go ahead and take a look at our util.lua, which we've made changes to.
因此 让我们继续查看我们的util.lua 我们已经对其进行了更改
And so what this is going to do is sort of do the same thing
所以它要做的是做同样的事情
that we did before.
就像我们以前做的那样
It has to iterate.
它必须迭代
So notice we have two rows of balls.
所以请注意 我们有两排球
We have these four and we have these three.
我们有这四个 我们有这三个
So we want to iterate four times.
所以我们想要迭代四次
You want to find whatever the offset is here,
你想知道这里的偏移量是多少
the X and Y. So it looks like three times 32 and then three times 16.
X和Y 所以看起来是3乘以32 然后是3乘以16
So 96 by--
所以96乘以--
I can't do math.
我不会做数学
Whatever 16 times three is.
不管16乘以3是什么
And then we'll end up 48.
然后我们就会变成48岁
And then we'll have--
然后我们会有--
which is what we do here.
这就是我们在这里所做的
So we have two iterations.
所以我们有两次迭代
So a four loop that goes from zero to three.
所以从零到三的四个循环
So the top row, the four.
所以最上面的一排 四个
We'll set a counter to one here.
我们在这里设一个柜台
And notice also 96 and 48.
还请注意96和48
That's the X and the Y that we're setting.
这是我们设定的X和Y
That's where the offset is for the individual ball sprites.
这就是各个球精灵的偏移量
Quads at counter gets--
柜台的四人组--
and notice also quads is a table.
请注意 四边形还有一张桌子
We're going to return this.
我们要把这个退掉
Quads at counter gets love.graphics.newquad at X, Y.
在柜台的四人组得到了爱
Eight pixels wide, eight pixels tall.
八个像素宽 八个像素高
That's how large the balls are.
这就是球的大小
And then we're going to add eight to it because we're going to the right.
然后我们再加8 因为我们要向右转
So this iteration just goes left to right.
所以这个迭代是从左到右的
And then here we're going to do basically X being set to 96
然后在这里 我们将基本上将X设置为96
and then Y to 56.
然后Y变为56
And then because we were editing X directly in here,
然后因为我们直接在这里编辑X
we want to reset X back to 96, but then also add
我们希望将X重置为96 但也要添加
the eight pixels so that we have the start for the next row
8个像素 这样我们就有了下一行的起点
vertically, so at Y 56.
纵向上 56日元也是如此
Do the exact same thing here, but only do it
在这里做完全相同的事情 但只做
three times because recall there is four balls on top
三次 因为回想一下 上面有四个球
and then three balls on bottom.
然后是底部的三个球
And then return it at the very end.
然后在最后还回来
And so now we have just an individual table.
所以现在我们只有一张单独的桌子
We don't need to keep like one monstrous table of quads,
我们不需要像一张巨大的四边形餐桌一样
which I find sort of disorganized.
我觉得这有点杂乱无章
We can just have a table of frames for the paddles,
我们可以只有一张划桨架的桌子
and the balls, and the bricks as we'll see.
还有球 还有我们将会看到的砖头
Actually, I have it up here I think.
实际上 我想我把它放在这里了
Maybe not.
也许不会
So in ball-- oh, actually, hold on.
所以在舞会上--哦 实际上 等等
Sorry.
抱歉的
So we were looking at--
所以我们在看--
I skipped over this one on accident.
我不小心跳过了这一条
So the bounce update.
所以弹跳更新
So everything I just said is relevant, but I accidentally
所以我刚才说的每件事都是相关的 但我不小心
hit that right two times.
向右打了两下
We want to go to the bounce update because this is slightly simpler.
我们想要转到退回更新 因为这稍微简单一些
So we were just talking about the ball, which is perfect.
所以我们只是在谈论球 这太完美了
So we're going to take the ball and then we're going to add that to the scene,
所以我们要拿着球 然后我们要把它添加到场景中
and we're just going to implement bouncing off the walls.
我们要做的就是从墙上跳起来
So actually, pretty identical to the code
所以实际上 与代码几乎完全相同
we saw for Pong where you just detect whether the ball has
我们看到了Pong 你只需要检测球是否有
gone past the left, right, or top edge of the screen.
超出屏幕的左、右或上边缘
In this case, it will also allow us to go to the bottom of the screen
在这种情况下 它还将允许我们转到屏幕底部
and we'll also implement colliding with the paddle
我们还将实现与球拍的碰撞
so then get a sense of the actual game play and what that feels like.
那么 你就可以感受到真正的游戏效果 以及那种感觉
So everything is currently current.
所以目前一切都是最新的
So we're going to go--
所以我们要去--
after talking about the function to actually get the individual ball
在谈到实际拿到个人球的功能后
quads out of the spreadsheet, we're going
从电子表格中拿出四元组 我们要
to look at the ball class which is going to allow us to spawn them in our scene.
来看看球类 它将允许我们在场景中产生它们
So a ball takes a width and height of eight.
所以球的宽度和高度都是8
No velocity.
没有速度
But we're going to allow ourselves to initialize the ball with the skin,
但我们将允许我们自己使用皮肤来初始化球
and we'll see this later just as a cutesy little thing to you
我们稍后会看到这是一个可爱的小东西给你
use the actual individual sprites rather than just one constant sprite.
使用实际的单个精灵 而不只是一个恒定的精灵
We're just going to give it a random number between one and seven
我们只会给它一个介于1和7之间的随机数
because there are seven quads.
因为有七个四边形
And then we'll just use gframes balls and math dot random number
然后我们将只使用格框、球和数学点随机数
to get the actual ball spread that we want.
才能得到我们想要的真正的球面
And so we have a simple collides function within ball
所以我们在球内有一个简单的碰撞函数
that would allow us to check to see whether we've collided with something
这将允许我们检查是否与某个物体相撞
that has a X, Y width and a height.
它具有X、Y宽度和高度
So it's a simple A, B collision detection.
所以这是一个简单的A B碰撞检测
And then here we have reset.
然后在这里我们有重置
Just resets it to the middle of the screen.
只需将其重置到屏幕中央即可
Update applies velocity.
更新应用速度
Stuff we've already seen.
我们已经看过的东西
This is where we actually implement bouncing off the walls.
这就是我们真正实现弹离墙壁的地方
So if X is less than or equal to zero, greater than
因此 如果X小于或等于零 则大于
or equal to virtual width minus eight, or less than or equal to zero,
或等于虚拟宽度减8 或小于或等于零
this should be where we reverse the velocity.
这应该是我们反转速度的地方
In the case of it bouncing off the left side, we want to reverse the X velocity
在它从左侧反弹的情况下 我们想要反转X速度
but keep it going up.
但要继续往上走
If it hits the top, then we want to reverse
如果它击中顶部 那么我们想要反转
the Y velocity to keep it moving in whatever direction it was moving.
Y速度 以保持它朝任何方向移动
And same thing with the right hand wall.
右手边的墙也是这样
And then play a wall hit sound.
然后播放一段墙壁上的热门音乐
And we're incorporating the sounds sort of as we go today
我们在今天的节目中融入了这些声音
just because they're so simple.
就因为它们太简单了
And it's also kind of nice just to have a little bit of feedback
仅仅得到一点反馈也是很好的
when you're actually endpoint of the game.
当你实际上是游戏的终点时
And the exact same code is here for drawing.
这里的绘图代码与此完全相同
So we have main texture, but now we're using gframes balls,
所以我们有主纹理 但现在我们使用的是GFrame球
and then we're indexing that at self.skin.
然后我们在self.kin上对其进行索引
And recall that we just set self.skin in here.
回想一下 我们刚刚在这里设置了self.kin
So all we need to do to just make it random
所以我们要做的就是把它随机
is just wherever we create a new ball, just give it a math.random7,
就是在我们创造一个新球的任何地方 给它一个数学运算
and then that will index into that quads table
然后 它将索引到那个四元表中
so we can draw a different ball texture each time.
这样我们每次都可以画出不同的球纹理
And so let's go ahead and see--
所以让我们继续下去 看看--
oh, actually, no.
哦 事实上 不是的
And one last thing we need to look at is the PlayState
我们需要关注的最后一件事是PlayState
has a little bit of new code as well.
也有一些新的代码
We're going to spawn a ball, so this is where we do it here.
我们要生一个球 所以这就是我们要做的
I'm not doing it random, but I could do it random here if I wanted to.
我不是随机做的 但如果我想的话 我可以在这里随机做
I could math.random7, and every time we boot up
我可以算术 随机7 而且每次我们启动的时候
the game it's going to be a different color because it's
这个游戏将会是不同的颜色 因为它
going to be a different skin.
将会是一张不同的皮肤
We need to update the ball.
我们需要更新一下球
So on line 50 we just update it like we do the paddle.
因此 在第50行 我们只需更新它 就像我们处理划桨一样
And then on line 52, we're just testing to see
然后在第52行 我们只是测试一下
whether it collides with the paddle because we're using just simple A,
它是否与球拍相撞 因为我们只用了简单的A
A, B, B. If it collides with the paddle, we can assume it was coming down.
如果它与球拍相撞 我们就可以假定它正在坠落
We can just reverse as delta Y.
我们可以反转为增量Y
Now, does anybody know what might be a current issue
现在 有谁知道什么可能是当前的问题
with the current implementation of this function?
该函数的当前实现情况如何？
Particularly with this line.
尤其是这条线
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: It will.
科尔顿·奥格登：会的
You're on the right track.
你走上了正确的道路
The answer was, if the ball is coming from the side,
答案是 如果球是从侧面传来的
it won't necessarily be bounced back up in the right Y direction.
它不一定会在正确的Y方向反弹回来
If it's coming from the side, it will always, in this case,
如果它是从侧面来的 在这种情况下 它总是
be coming from up above.
是从上面来的
So it always still be reversing in the right delta Y.
因此 在右增量Y中 它总是在倒转
But what's going to happen if it comes in at an angle
但如果它以一个角度进入会发生什么
and then isn't basically reset?
然后基本上不是重置了吗？
Like right now if it comes at an angle and it
就像现在 如果它从一个角度来 它
gets caught-- let's say it's like below the top edge of the paddle.
被抓到了--比方说它就像是在桨的顶端下方
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: You're going to get an infinite collision
科尔顿·奥格登：你会有一个无限的碰撞
loop because we're not resetting it's position,
循环 因为我们没有重置它的位置
we're only updating its velocity.
我们只是在更新它的速度
If it comes in at the right angle from the side,
如果它从侧面以正确的角度进入
it's going to get stuck inside the paddle
它会卡在球拍里
and then it's going to cause a little bit of funky behavior.
然后 它会导致一些时髦的行为
I'll try and see if I can make that happen in my demonstration here.
我会试着在我的演示中实现这一点
But that's the gist of all of these updates.
但这就是所有这些更新的要点
So if we go to Start, we can see immediately we have a ball.
因此 如果我们开始 我们可以立即看到我们有一个球
And when it hits the sides or the top, it bounces accordingly.
当它撞到侧面或顶部时 它会相应地反弹
It hits the paddle.
它击中了球拍
So when it comes in from the top flush on the top, it flips the Y velocity.
因此 当它从顶部进入时 它会翻转Y速度
Let's see if I can get it at an angle here.
让我们看看我能不能从这个角度拍到它
There it is.
这就是了
It'll get stuck.
它会卡住的
And so whenever you sort of do A, A, B, B collision detection,
所以每当你进行A、A、B、B碰撞检测时
just remember to always reset the position of whatever it
只要记住总是重置它的位置就行了
is that collided that's moving so that it doesn't clip
它是被碰撞的 正在移动的 所以它不会卡住
and get stuck inside of something else over and over again.
一次又一次地被困在别的东西里
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: The question is I'm always doing love space dot,
科尔顿·奥格登：问题是我一直在做爱情空间点
and as opposed to just running things from using
而不是仅仅使用
the complete path of whatever the file is, in order to do that-- so are you
任何文件的完整路径 为了做到这一点--您也是
on a Mac or a Windows machine?
在Mac还是Windows机器上？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: So on a Windows machine it is a little trickier,
科尔顿·奥格登：所以在Windows系统上 这就有点棘手了
but I've found a really nice sort of plug-in for VS Code.
但我已经找到了一种非常好的VS代码插件
So if you're VS Code, which is the editor that I use, it has plug-ins
因此 如果您使用的是VS Code 这是我使用的编辑器 它有插件
and one of the plug-ins that you can download is for Love2D
你可以下载的其中一个插件是Love2D
and it has a config where if you just press Alt L,
它有一个配置 如果你只需按下Alt L
it will run whatever directory you're currently in,
它将运行您当前所在目录
whatever project you're currently in.
无论你目前参与的是什么项目
It will call Love.
它将呼唤爱
It adds it to your path for you.
它会为你把它添加到你的道路上
So download the Love2D plug-in on VS code if you want that to work.
因此 如果您想让它工作 请下载VS代码上的Love2D插件
I'm on a Mac, so I can edit what's called my batch profile,
我在Mac上 所以我可以编辑我的批次配置文件
and alias Love to its complete path in my file system.
并将其别名Love添加到我文件系统中的完整路径
And you can do the same thing with--
你也可以做同样的事情--
I don't know how it would work with Windows in terms of aliasing,
我不知道Windows在别名方面是如何工作的
but it's essentially the same thing as typing out the entire path to Love,
但从本质上讲 这与输入通向爱的整个道路是一样的
but only I'm changing it to another word.
不过 我要换个词
I'm changing it to Love.
我要把它改成爱
So I'm setting Love equals to application slash
所以我将Love设置为应用程序斜杠
love.app/content/resources et cetera.
Love.app/内容/资源等
So good question.
问得好
I would download on Windows.
我会在Windows上下载
I'm a big fan of VS Code and the Love2D plug-in.
我是VS Code和Love2D插件的铁杆粉丝
I would recommend looking into that.
我建议你调查一下这个问题
And I'm sure there are other plug-ins, and there's a page also
我相信还有其他插件 还有一个页面
on the website--
在网站上--
I don't have a browser open at the moment.
我目前没有打开浏览器
But on the wiki, you can look at the Getting Started page.
但在维基上 你可以看到入门页面
I believe it's like love2d.com/wiki/gettingstarted.
我相信这就像是love2d.com/wiki/gettingstarted
They have a bunch of instructions for different operating
他们有一堆不同操作的说明
systems and different text editors that allow you to get sort
允许您进行排序的系统和不同的文本编辑器
of a more efficient workflow going.
更高效的工作流程
So any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好的
So we did the bounce update.
所以我们做了弹跳更新
Now we can finally edit the bricks.
现在我们终于可以编辑砖块了
Add in the bricks, I should say.
我要说的是 再加上砖头
So these are pretty simple.
所以这些都很简单
So we're going to take a look at it.
所以我们要来看看它
And right now we're not going to do any sort of fancy procedural generation,
现在我们不会做任何花哨的程序世代
we're just going to get some bricks on the screen.
我们只是要在屏幕上放几块砖
Just some easy bricks.
只是一些简单的砖块
Or rather, we will get some very basic procedural generation,
或者更确切地说 我们将得到一些非常基本的程序性生成
but not to the level that we'll see soon.
但不会达到我们很快就会看到的水平
We'll see that very soon.
我们很快就会看到这一点
OK.
好的
So I'm going to go into my main.lua here.
所以我要进入我的主 Lua在这里
I'm going to go into the Breakout3.
我要进入《越狱3》
And same thing that we did before on line 67,
和我们之前在第67行做的相同的事情
we just have a new bricks table in our gframes.
我们的框架里只有一张新的砖桌
And it just generate quads bricks.
它只会产生四边形的砖块
We call from util.lua, so we can look at that really quick as well.
我们从util.lua调用 所以我们也可以快速查看它
This one's actually really easy.
这个其实很简单
Sourceutil.lua.
Sourceutil.Lua
Because they start at the very top of the screen,
因为它们从屏幕的最顶端开始
we can assume that-- we could effectively
我们可以假设--我们可以有效地
treat this whole thing as if it were just these
把这整件事当做是这些
and just generate quads at a constant width and height
并且只生成宽度和高度恒定的四边形
because, effectively, we only need a subset of the frames that's generating.
因为 实际上 我们只需要正在生成的帧的一个子集
Because it's generating them this way, top to bottom, left to right,
因为它是这样产生它们的 从上到下 从左到右
we can just grab all the way up to here using
我们可以一直抓取到这里 用
table.slice, which we saw before, and not
表 切片 我们之前看到的 而不是
worry about indexing into any weird, like,
担心索引到任何奇怪的 比如
having any constants X and Y that we need to index with in order
具有需要按顺序编制索引的任何常量X和Y
to get an offset.
以获得补偿
We can just do a very simple--
我们可以做一个非常简单的--
if we go down to line 57, generate quads bricks, it just does a table.slice.
如果我们往下到第57行 生成四块砖 它只做一张表 切片
And so within that, we're going to generate quads atlas 32,16.
在此基础上 我们将生成四元地图集32 16
So this is going to have the effect of dividing up our sprite sheet by 32
这将产生将我们的精灵工作表除以32的效果
by 16 pieces.
以16块为单位
It's going to generate all of these just fine,
它会很好地产生所有这些
but then it's going to have quads here, here, here, here, here
但它会在这里 这里有四个四边形
that don't line up with the quads that you see here
与你在这里看到的四边形不对齐
because it's just blindly assuming that all of the sprites in that sheet
因为它只是盲目地假设那张纸上的所有精灵
are the same size because that's all we're doing.
都是一样的大小 因为这就是我们要做的
We're just calling generate quads, which if you recall,
我们只是调用生成四元组 如果您还记得的话
just generates a fixed size width and height throughout our entire atlas,
只是在我们的整个地图集中生成固定大小的宽度和高度
which is great for a lot of sheets that are symmetrical,
这对于许多对称的床单来说是很棒的
but there are cases where we have, like, for example here, where
但在某些情况下 比如在这里
our spreadsheet is asymmetrical.
我们的电子表格是不对称的
We have paddles of differing sizes, we have
我们有不同大小的球拍 我们有
the balls which are eight by eight, we have the bricks,
八乘八的球 我们有砖头
we have the other power ups at the bottom.
我们在底部有其他加电装置
But the generate quads bricks takes in that table
但生成的四边形砖块占据了那张桌子
that we're generating, which is going to be a bunch of frames
我们正在生成的 这将是一堆帧
that we don't want.
这是我们不想要的
Many of them clipped, half clipped.
他们中的许多人剪掉了 一半剪掉了
And then we're just going to take it from one to 21.
然后我们就把它从1变为21
And when we do that, one to 21 is effectively-- that's how many of these
当我们这样做的时候 1到21实际上是--这就是这些
there are.
确实有
So 18 and then one, two, three.
所以是18 然后是1 2 3
So from one to 21, all of those.
所以从1到21 所有这些都是
That will be all the bricks.
这将是所有的砖
We can throw away all the rest of the quads
我们可以扔掉所有剩下的四边形
and just blindly assume that they're all the same size.
然后盲目地假设它们都是一样大小的
So any questions on how quads or how any of these tables are working?
那么 对于四元组如何工作或这些桌子是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
So we're going to go ahead.
所以我们要继续下去
We have a new class now, brick.lua.
我们现在有一个新的班级 布里克·卢亚
So simple building blocks.
如此简单的积木
In brick.lua on line 30, we have a flag called in play.
在第30行的brick.lua中 我们有一面名为in play的旗帜
self.inplay gets true.
自我陶醉成真
And so we're just going to use this to render.
所以我们只需要用这个来渲染
We're just going to say, if it's in play, render it.
我们只想说 如果它在起作用 就渲染它
If it's not, don't render it.
如果不是 则不要呈现它
It's that simple.
就这么简单
That way we don't have to worry about object deallocation or anything fancy.
这样我们就不必担心对象重新分配或任何花哨的事情了
We have all of our bricks and whether it's in play
我们已经准备好了所有的砖块 以及它是否正在发挥作用
or not, render it or perform update logic.
或者不是 呈现它或执行更新逻辑
And if it's not in play, just pretend it doesn't exist.
如果它不存在 就假装它不存在
Just ignore it.
忽略它就好
We're only going to have like 30 or I don't know how many,
我们只会有30人 或者我不知道有多少人
13 max by four bricks in our scene at once, so worrying about freeing memory
在我们的场景中 一次最多13 x 4块砖 所以担心内存释放
isn't really an issue.
其实并不是什么问题
But if you have a million different things getting generated all the time,
但是如果你有一百万种不同的东西一直在产生
having simple in play is false might not always
在游戏中拥有简单可能并不总是错误的
be viable because you need to store all that memory for all those objects.
这是可行的 因为您需要存储所有这些对象的所有内存
So just a shortcut here, but not necessarily best
所以这里只是一条捷径 但不一定是最好的
practice for very large games.
为大型比赛做练习
But certainly great and simple for small games.
但对于小游戏来说 这无疑是既好又简单的
On line 37, we define a function called brick hit.
在第37行 我们定义了一个名为Brick Hit的函数
And all this does is just play a sound effect and set in play to false.
所有这些都只是播放音效 并将其设置为假
And so all we're going to do is just check
所以我们要做的就是检查
to see whether there's a collision and then just call this hit function,
来查看是否存在冲突 然后调用此Hit函数
play a sound, and then just pretend it doesn't exist anymore.
播放一个声音 然后假装它不再存在
And then render, all render does is if it's in play, check the in play flag,
然后渲染 渲染所做的就是如果它正在播放 检查正在播放的标志
draw main at bricks or using our bricks table here that we created.
在砖块处绘制Main 或使用我们创建的砖桌
And then we're going to start at one and then
然后我们从一点开始 然后
we're going to index it based on our color minus one times four,
我们将根据我们的颜色减去1乘以4来索引它
and then we're going to add it's tier.
然后我们要添加它的层
So there are, if you recall, one, two, three, four,
所以 如果你还记得的话 有一 二 三 四
five colors and four tiers.
五种颜色 四个层次
And so what we're going to do is we're going to jump between the colors.
所以我们要做的是在不同的颜色之间跳跃
So we'll go value one, value two, value three, value four, value five.
所以我们会得到值1 值2 值3 值4 值5
That will be our first five or I guess six.
这将是我们的前五个 或者我想是六个
That will be our first six bricks.
这将是我们的头六块砖
And then we're going to go one, two, three-- or we're going to add,
然后我们将开始一 二 三--或者我们将添加
we're going to have a tier basically.
我们基本上会有一个层次
It'll be one, two, three, or four.
可能是一、二、三或四
And if it's at tier one, then we can just add--
如果是在第一级 那么我们可以添加--
basically to index into whatever tier we're on,
基本上是索引到我们所在的任何一层
we just need to add tier minus one to whatever our index is.
无论我们的索引是什么 我们只需添加减一级即可
So here if our tier is one, then we just want to render this block.
所以在这里 如果我们的层是一层 那么我们只想渲染这个块
We don't want to go to the next one.
我们不想去下一家
So we're just going to say tier minus one.
所以我们就说一级减去一级
We're going to add--
我们将添加--
so one minus one is zero.
所以一减一等于零
So we're going at zero to this, get this.
所以我们从零开始 明白这一点
But if tiers two, we'll add one, and two, and three.
但如果是第二级 我们会增加一级、二级和三级
And then we just multiply whatever brick we want by our color.
然后我们只需将我们想要的任何砖乘以我们的颜色
Multiply it by four to get an offset for whatever our actual color is.
将它乘以4 就可以得到我们实际颜色的偏移量
So we take our color, figure out where on the sheet it is,
所以我们选择我们的颜色 找出它在床单上的位置
and then just add our tier to it in order to index
然后只需将我们的层添加到其中 以便为其编制索引
into our spreadsheet accordingly.
添加到我们的电子表格中
And so that's what the math here is doing.
这就是数学所要做的
And if we go back to our PlayState--
如果我们回到PlayState--
and I'm going to start moving a little bit faster
我要开始走得更快一点
just so we can keep caught up.
这样我们就能跟上进度了
But in our PlayState, one thing that we notice here,
但在我们的PlayState中 我们在这里注意到一件事
we have a new class called level maker that we're seeing,
我们看到了一个名为Level Maker的新班级
which was a function called createmap.
这是一个名为createmap的函数
We're going to take out all the logic for generating our levels
我们将去掉所有产生我们的关卡的逻辑
and we're just going to put it in one place.
我们只需要把它放在一个地方
We're going to call that level maker.
我们要给那个关卡制造者打电话
Rather than in our different states that maybe
而不是在我们不同的州 也许
generate the bricks like the PlayState or I
生成像PlayState或I一样的积木
guess it would be the ServeState, VictoryState,
我猜应该是ServeState VictoryState
I guess, rather than generating all the bricks
我猜 而不是产生所有的砖
in that state within it's innate code, let's just make a level maker
在其固有代码状态下 让我们创建一个关卡标记器
and we can just say, OK, set bricks to levelmaker.createmap,
我们可以说 好的 把砖放到平地上 创建地图
which will return a table of bricks.
这将返回一张桌子的砖块
Same-- excuse me-- logic as we saw before.
抱歉 逻辑和我们之前看到的一样
In this case, we're just going to iterate for k brick
在本例中 我们将迭代k Brick
in pairs of self.bricks.
成对的自家的砖块
If the brick's in play and it collides, if the ball collides with it,
如果砖块在比赛中发生碰撞 如果球与之相撞
then hit it, which will set it not into play.
然后击打它 这将使它不再发挥作用
So simple A, A, B, B.
很简单的A A B B
And then lastly, we have our render logic here,
最后 我们这里有我们的呈现逻辑
which is going to take that bricks table and just iterate over it.
它会把那张砖头桌子拿来 然后迭代
And the last thing we should probably look at
我们最不应该看到的就是
is the actual level maker itself, which in this case is very simple,
是真正的关卡制造者本身 在这种情况下很简单
but we'll see it gets a little bit more complicated later when we do it.
但我们稍后会看到 它会变得更复杂
When we have a more elaborate procedural generation approach to our levels.
当我们有一个更详细的程序性生成方法来处理我们的级别时
But right now, we're just going to say set two random variables here.
但现在 我们只需要在这里设置两个随机变量
Number of rows and columns.
行数和列数
And then for every row or for basically every row and every column,
然后对于每行或基本上每行和每列
create a new brick.
创建一块新砖
And then there's some math here.
然后这里有一些数学问题
I'm going to kind of skim over it, but basically it
我会略读一下 但基本上
calculates where the brick is and then gives us
计算砖块的位置 然后给我们
eight pixels of padding on either side.
两边各有八个像素的填充
And then based on how many it is, it needs to center all
然后根据它的数量 它需要将所有
the bricks and shift them by a certain amount to the left
然后把砖向左移动一定的量
and then start drawing all of them.
然后开始把它们都画出来
And that's essentially what this code does here.
这就是这段代码在这里的基本功能
So calculate the center.
所以计算中心
I wrote it out in comments here, but I'm going
我在这里的评论中写下了 但我要去
just kind of glaze over it for now.
只是暂时不去想它
But effectively, center all the bricks.
但实际上 把所有的砖块放在中间
Basically calculate what offset on the X-axis you need to put all of them
基本上计算什么样的偏移量在X轴上你需要把所有的人
so that they appear centered, and then you're going to draw them all out.
让它们看起来居中 然后把它们都画出来
And then that's it for the level maker class.
这就是水平仪制造者课程的内容
So simply number of rows and columns, and then fill a table with bricks
所以简单的行数和列数 然后用砖块填满一个表
but set their X equal to however much we need to center all
但是把它们的X设为我们需要的
of them when they're all drawn out.
当他们都被拉出来的时候
So we need to figure, we need to basically take in our number of columns
所以我们需要计算 我们需要基本上把我们的列数
into account when we do that.
在我们这样做的时候
And then if we go into Breakout3 and run that, we have bricks.
然后如果我们进入Breakout3并运行它 我们就有了砖块
They're getting collided with, and as soon as they get hit,
它们会被撞上 一旦它们被撞上
collided are in play on each of those bricks gets set to false
碰撞在这些砖块中的每一个都被设置为假
and they no longer get rendered.
它们不再被渲染
And they no longer get updated in terms of collision.
它们不再更新碰撞方面
Now, we still have the issue with the ball not getting reset.
现在 我们仍然有问题的球没有得到重置
We'll fix that.
我们会解决的
That's an easy fix.
很容易搞定
But we're coming a long way.
但我们已经走了很远了
We have things moving at quite a pace.
我们的进展相当快
I'm going to go ahead and move to the next bit of code here.
我将继续前进 并移动到下一个代码位
So this is another bit of code.
这是另一段代码
I'm going to sort of glaze over a little bit of the details here.
我会在这里稍微忽略一些细节
But at a high level what we need to do is it's one thing
但在高层次上 我们需要做的是
to detect that we've collided with a brick,
来检测我们是否撞上了一块砖头
but in Breakout, the ball bounces off of the brick
但在《越狱》里 球会从砖块上弹开
depending on which side it hits.
这取决于它击中的是哪一边
And we don't know this necessarily just based off of the collision.
我们不能仅仅根据碰撞就知道这一点
We just know whether the collision is true or not.
我们只知道碰撞是真是假
We don't know where it came from and how much it collided with.
我们不知道它从哪里来 也不知道它与多少物体相撞
And then we're also going to fix our paddles so that rather than-- because
然后我们还要固定我们的桨
currently all it does is just negate whatever the Y velocity is,
目前它所做的只是否定Y速度
but we want to add a little bit more variety
但我们想增加一点变化
to how we end up sort of ricocheting the ball off the paddle when we play
当我们打球的时候
so that we can sort of strategize a little bit,
这样我们就能制定一点策略
give ourselves a little bit of game play.
给我们自己一点游戏的机会
So if we are moving to the right and we hit the right edge of the puddle
所以 如果我们向右移动 我们碰到了水坑的右边
with the ball, it should probably go in a sharper direction.
有了球 它可能会朝着更锋利的方向前进
Same thing with the left side.
左边也是一样
And we can effectively do that by taking the middle,
而我们可以通过选择中间部分来有效地做到这一点
figuring out how far away from the center it is,
计算出它离中心有多远
and then just amplifying our delta X in the negative or positive direction
然后在负或正的方向上放大我们的增量X
based off of that.
在此基础上
And that has the effect of causing that to happen.
而这会导致这种情况的发生
So here we can see we have the ball sort of coming at the paddle,
所以在这里我们可以看到我们的球有点像是在划桨
and let's pretend that the paddle is moving to the left.
让我们假设球拍正在向左移动
In this case, however far away the ball is from the center,
在这种情况下 无论球离中心有多远
we want to scale that by some amount and then
我们希望按一定的比例进行调整 然后
end up making that our negative delta X, because that's effectively
最终使它成为负的增量X 因为这实际上是
how the game normally works.
这个游戏通常是怎么运作的
If you move the paddle to the left or the right,
如果你把球拍向左或向右移动
hit it on a corner or something, gives it that sharp angle.
在拐角或其他什么地方击球 给它一个尖锐的角度
And that's effectively what the sharp angle is.
而这实际上就是尖锐的角度
It's just a strong delta X, and it gets amplified the larger this is.
它只是一个很强的增量X 并且它被放大得越大
So just basically take this, multiply it by some amount,
所以基本上就是把这个 乘以某个数值
and then make it negative or positive on your dx.
然后在你的DX上设置为负值或正值
That's your sort of paddle collision V2.
这就是你的划桨碰撞V2
Brick collision is a little bit--
砖块碰撞有点--
it's pretty simple, but it's a little bit more complicated.
这很简单 但有点复杂
Basically what we need to do is just check and see which edge of the ball
基本上 我们需要做的就是检查一下 看看球的哪边
isn't inside the brick.
不在砖头里面
And so if the left edge of the-- and we can also sort of
所以如果左边的边缘--我们也可以
simplify this a little bit.
稍微简化一下
If the left-- as you see here by the pseudocode--
如果左边--就像你在这里看到的伪代码--
if the left edge of the ball is outside the brick and the dx is positive,
如果球的左边缘在砖外并且DX为正
then we can say, oh, we can basically assume
然后我们可以说 哦 我们基本上可以假设
we've come in from the left side, so we should probably
我们是从左边进来的 所以我们应该
go in the opposite Y direction on the left side.
在左侧朝相反的Y方向行驶
Or sorry, we should go in the same Y direction, but negate our delta
或者很抱歉 我们应该朝同一个Y方向前进 但要取消我们的增量
X. Because we're coming in from the left,
因为我们是从左边进来的
the left side is outside the brick, so bounce it back.
左边在砖块外面 所以把它弹回来
And the same thing for the right edge.
同样的道理也适用于右边
And we only do this test, the left edge of the ball, if dx is positive.
我们只做这个测试 球的左边 如果dx是正数
Because if dx is negative, there's no way
因为如果DX是负值 就不可能
the ball's colliding with the left side of our brick.
球撞到了我们的砖的左侧
So we can shortcut that effectively.
所以我们可以有效地走捷径
We do the same exact logic here, just on the right edge
我们在这里做同样的逻辑 只是在正确的边缘
of the brick instead of the left edge.
而不是左边的边缘
And then if none of those hold true, we're
如果这些都不成立 我们就会
going to see if the top edge of the ball is above the top edge of the brick.
去看看球的顶边是否在砖头的顶边之上
And if that's the case, we know that we've hit from the top.
如果是这样的话 我们知道我们是从顶端开始的
We can trigger a top collision.
我们可以触发顶部碰撞
And if none of those have held true, we know
如果这些都不成立 我们知道
that we have had a collision of some kind,
我们发生了某种碰撞
we can just register a bottom collision.
我们可以只登记一次底部碰撞
And so this is a simple version of this sort
所以这是这个排序的一个简单版本
of way of doing Breakout collision.
做突破碰撞的方式
It has a few faults when it comes to corners,
它在弯道方面有一些缺陷
sometimes corners can be a little bit finicky,
有时弯道可能有点挑剔
but I would say it works 99% of the time.
但我要说的是 它99%的情况下都是有效的
For a much more robust and a better example, I would look at this URL
要获得一个更健壮、更好的示例 我将查看以下URL
here because he also goes into a full sort of breakdown
这是因为他也陷入了全面的崩溃
of how he would implement arkanoid, which is the same thing effectively
他将如何实施阿卡诺德 这是同样的事情有效地
as Breakout if you just want an alternative look at it.
如果你只是想从另一个角度看它 那就作为突破口
But basically, his solution involved taking how much the X and the Y
但基本上 他的解决方案包括取X和Y的多少
differed on different points of the bricks relative to the ball.
在砖块相对于球的不同点上有所不同
And I believe he also kept the ball as an actual ball with a center point,
我相信他也把球当做一个有中心点的真正的球
even though he rendered it as a rectangle.
尽管他把它渲染成了一个长方形
So it's a little bit more robust.
所以它更坚固了一点
I decided to implement it a simpler way, which I'll showcase,
我决定以一种更简单的方式实现它 我将展示这一点
which is the way that I demonstrated because it worked well
这就是我演示的方式 因为它工作得很好
and it wasn't too much code to sort of look over.
这并不是太多的代码 几乎看不出来
But I do encourage you to take a look at that.
但我鼓励你去看看这一点
We're going to look at our PlayState now in Breakout4.
我们将在《突破4》中看看我们的PlayState
And in our PlayState, we're going to see--
在我们的PlayState中 我们将看到--
sorry.
抱歉的
Line 65.
65行
So this is the actual paddle code for influencing the ball's delta X.
这就是影响球的增量X的实际球拍代码
So basically, if the ball.x is less than the paddle.x plus it's width divided
所以基本上 如果球x小于球桨x加上它的宽度
by two, so basically on the left side of the paddle,
两个人 所以基本上在划桨的左边
and the paddle's delta X is less than zero, which means it's moving left--
划桨的增量X小于零 这意味着它在向左移动--
because we don't really want to necessarily influence it if we're just
因为我们真的不想影响它 如果我们只是
standing still--
原地踏步--
we're going to do what I described earlier.
我们要做我之前描述过的事情
We're going to give it some scaler, like some start off value.
我们要给它一些定标器 比如一些起始值
In this case, negative 50 is just sort of seeding this, giving it
在这种情况下 负50只是在某种程度上播种 给它
some sort of initial value.
某种初值
And then we're just going to subtract the ball's X from the middle point.
然后我们只需从中点减去球的X
This being the middle point of the paddle
这是划桨的中点
And then just multiply it by eight.
然后再乘以8
So whatever the difference is between the ball's X and the middle
所以不管球的X和中间有什么不同
of the paddle, multiply it by eight.
划桨的数乘以八
Add it to negative 50 and then negate that.
把它加到负50 然后再求反
Also negate that whole value so that the whole entire value becomes negative.
同时否定该整数值 从而使整个整数值变为负值
And we, therefore, get a sharper delta X depending on which angle
因此 我们得到了更清晰的增量X 这取决于哪个角度
it's coming at, and also how fast--
它正在到来 也是以多快的速度--
or not how fast, but whether or not we are moving left.
或者不是速度有多快 而是我们是否在向左移动
And it's the exact same thing on the right side.
右边也是一样的东西
Only because we're taking this math, this self.paddle.x
只是因为我们要学这个数学 这个self.paddle.x
plus self.paddle.width divided by two minus the ball.x,
加上自拍宽度除以2减去球宽x
the ball.x isn't going to be greater than that point.
Ball.x不会大于那个点
So this value is actually going to be negative.
所以这个值实际上是负值
So we're going to just make it positive with math.abs.
所以我们只需要用Math.abs来证明这一点
So absolute value.
所以绝对值
Just a lua function.
只是一个Lua函数
So the absolute value of the difference between the ball's
所以球与球之间的差值的绝对值
X and the middle point times eight, add it to 50,
X和中间点乘以8 加到50
and that'll give us a positive value that scales depending on whether or not
这将给我们一个正值 它的大小取决于
we've hit the middle of the, we've hit the right edge of the paddle
我们打到了中间 我们打到了桨的右边
and are moving to the right.
正在向右移动
And so that's, in a nutshell, how we get that collision to work with the paddle
所以 简而言之 这就是我们如何让碰撞与划桨一起工作
and how we can tweak delta X to be scaled a little bit more
以及我们如何将增量X调整得更大一些
than just a constant, you know, negative or whatever
而不只是一个常量 你知道的 负数或其他什么
it's current X was, but negative dy.
它是当前的x 但是是负的dy
A little bit more complicated.
稍微复杂一点
And then the actual collision code for the bricks
然后是砖块的实际碰撞代码
themselves is going to take place in a for loop here.
它们将在这里的for循环中发生
So if it's in play, if the ball collides with it, hit it.
因此 如果它在比赛中 如果球与它相撞 就击打它
So I added plus two.
所以我加了加二
So the gist of the math is if ball.x is less than brick.x
所以数学的要点是 如果bal.x小于brick.x
and the ball is moving to the right, self.ball.dx is greater than zero,
球向右移动 self.ball.dx大于零
then flip it's X velocity.
然后将其翻转为X速度
So bounce it to the left.
所以把它弹到左边
That's what this check is.
这张支票就是这么回事
But it plays a little bit rough with corners
但它在角球上打得有点粗糙
because you could theoretically get into a position
因为从理论上讲 你可以进入一个
where you come in at an angle and it's intersecting
你以一个角度进入 它是相交的
with the paddle in two positions, both on top and the left
将球拍放在两个位置 都在顶部和左侧
or on bottom and the left.
或者在底部和左边
So in that case, adding two sort of prioritizes the Y being hit.
因此 在这种情况下 添加两个将确定命中的Y的优先顺序
So it basically takes the check from the exposition of the ball to the X plus 2.
所以它基本上是从球的展开式到X加2的检查
And so it ends up fixing the corners a little bit, but the gist of it
因此 它最终修复了一些角落 但它的要点是
is just check to see if the ball.x is less than the brick.x.
只需检查Ball.x是否小于brick.x
And if it is and we've detected a collision, we can bounce it.
如果是这样 并且我们检测到了碰撞 我们可以将其弹回
There are some subtle corner case bugs without adding this plus two,
在没有加上这个加二的情况下 有一些微妙的角落问题
so we add that.
所以我们加上了这一点
And then flip the velocity here.
然后在这里反转速度
Oh, this shift here.
哦 这个班次
This is what we were talking about earlier with make sure
这就是我们之前谈到的确保
when you do a collision, shift whatever is
当你做碰撞时 移动任何
moving outside the boundaries of whatever you're colliding with.
走出你正在碰撞的任何东西的界限
So self.ball.x gets brick.x minus eight because the ball is eight pixels wide.
因此 self.ball.x得到的是brick.x减去8 因为球有8个像素宽
It should actually be self.ball.width for a better style,
为了获得更好的风格 它实际上应该是self.ball
but that's essentially what it translates out to.
但这就是它本质上要转化为的
Same thing for the right edge.
右边的边缘也是这样
The plus six because it's on the right side.
正六是因为它在右边
So it's effectively the same thing as minus two if we're on the left side.
所以如果我们在左边 它实际上和负2是一样的
Just a sort of fixes corners, weird issues with corners.
只是一种修复转角的方法 转角的奇怪问题
But check in to see if basically the ball plus its height minus two
但检查一下 基本上球是不是加上它的高度减2
is greater than the brick plus X plus brick.width, which it means,
大于砖块加X加砖块宽度 这意味着
oh, we've collided with the right edge of the screen, of the brick.
哦 我们撞到了屏幕的右边 砖头的右边
And then if the Y is less than the brick.y,
然后如果Y小于砖块Y
then we've collided with the top of the brick,
然后我们撞上了砖头的顶部
and otherwise, we've collided with the bottom.
否则 我们就撞到了底部
And with the top and the bottom, just do the same thing we did with delta X,
对于顶部和底部 只要做我们对增量X所做的相同的事情
but do it with delta Y, but you're still resetting it.
但对Delta Y进行此操作 但您仍在重新设置它
So ball.y gets brick.y minus eight.
因此 Ball.y得到brick.y减去8
Ball.y gets brick.y plus 16 because the paddle or the individual bricks
Ball.y得到brick.y加16 因为球拍或单独的砖
are 16 pixels tall.
有16个像素高
That's the gist of the collision detection.
这就是碰撞检测的要点
And then if we actually-- oh, and one other thing that I ended up
然后如果我们真的--哦 还有一件事 我最终
putting here just to make it a little bit more interesting,
把它放在这里只是为了让它更有趣一些
and this also ties into more complicated collision detection.
这也与更复杂的碰撞检测有关
If your velocity is too fast, a lot of the time it'll skip through objects,
如果你的速度太快 很多时候它会跳过物体
and then that causes a lot of problems with these collision detection
这就给这些碰撞检测带来了很多问题
functions that normally are very sort of mathematically correct
这些函数通常在数学上是非常正确的
and they work well.
它们工作得很好
They don't work well when it skips over what
当它跳过什么时 它们就不能很好地工作
you're trying to actually collide with.
你实际上正试图与之相撞
So a solution to that, which was beyond the scope of this example but something
这个问题的解决方案超出了本例的范围 但是
we're thinking about, is perhaps stepping backwards a certain amount
我们在想 可能是在倒退到一定程度
of time, a certain amount of pixels.
时间 一定的像素量
Perhaps maybe start at where you where your ball was on one particular,
也许可以从你的球所在的地方开始
on the last frame, and then just add its width and height to itself
在最后一帧上 然后只需将其宽度和高度添加到其自身
until it collides with something, until it reaches whatever its current delta X
直到它与某物相撞 直到它到达当前的增量X
or delta Y plus its position is.
或者Y增量加上它的位置
That's one way to do it.
这是一种方法
Sort of just adding a bunch of invisible--
就像是添加了一堆看不见的--
whatever you're colliding with or whatever you're using to collide--
无论你撞上的是什么 或者你用来碰撞的是什么--
add a bunch of invisible those to bridge the gap and check into if any of those
添加一堆看不见的那些来弥合差距 并检查其中任何一个
hold true for a collision.
对于碰撞 保持为True
A little bit more computationally expensive, but a lot more accurate
计算成本稍微高一点 但精确度要高得多
in terms of the physics.
从物理学的角度来说
And aside from that, everything is the same.
除此之外 一切都是一样的
So if you look at the code in Breakout4--
所以如果你看一下Breakout 4中的代码--
and I'm going to go a little bit faster henceforth.
从今以后 我要开得更快一点
That's probably the meatiest part of the program.
这可能是该计划中最丰盛的部分
We get collisions.
我们会遇到碰撞
And then I'll try and get a strong angle so I can demo the--
然后我会试着得到一个强有力的角度 这样我就可以演示--
that didn't work.
但这并不管用
That actually gave a weaker angle.
这实际上给出了一个较弱的角度
So if you do this and you do it close to the center, it has the opposite effect.
所以如果你这样做 你靠近中心做 它会产生相反的效果
But there you go.
但这就是你要做的
That's a sharper angle.
这是一个更锐利的角度
So now you can actually influence the ball in a little bit more
所以现在你实际上可以更多地影响球
of a personable way.
风度翩翩的方式
You know, not just have it be a flat delta Y gets negative--
你知道 它不仅仅是一个平坦的增量 Y变负--
or get negative delta Y effectively.
或者有效地得到负的增量Y
So any questions on sort of how the gist of all of that works?
那么对于这一切的主旨是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
Perfect.
完美无缺
So now we're going to get into a little bit more of some fun stuff.
所以现在我们要进入更多一些有趣的东西
We'll do a couple more examples, then we'll take a break.
我们再做几个例子 然后休息一下
So this is the hearts update.
这就是心脏的最新情况
So notice that the very top of the screen, as I've demonstrated in these
请注意屏幕的最上方 正如我在下面这些演示中所演示的
slides, we have just a few hearts.
幻灯片 我们只有几颗心
One of them is empty.
其中一个是空的
We showed this earlier.
我们早些时候展示了这个
And then we have a game over screen, which is our final score.
然后我们有一场屏幕上的比赛 这是我们的最终比分
So I'm going to go ahead and we're just going to look at the code a little bit
所以我要继续 我们只需要稍微看一下代码
faster now since a lot of the stuff is fairly straightforward.
现在更快了 因为很多东西都相当简单
I'm going to go ahead and open up the--
我要继续下去 打开--
I'm going to make sure I'm in the right folder first of all.
我首先要确保我在正确的文件夹中
Breakout5.
突破5.
And then in the--
然后在--
so one other thing we're going to start doing is--
所以我们要开始做的另一件事是--
I mentioned this earlier.
我刚才提到过这一点
And it's going to be it's going to hold true
它将会是真实的
for any of the sort of state transformations
对于任何一种状态转换
that take place going forward.
这一切都发生在未来
Rather than keep global variables, we're going
我们没有保留全局变量 而是
to sort of do away with that idea outside of the asset tables
在某种程度上消除资产表外的这种想法
that we have just because those are kind of an exception
我们所拥有的只是因为这些是一种例外
and they could reasonably be put into a separate class called the resource
并且可以合理地将它们放在一个称为资源的单独类中
manager.
经理
We're going to start passing in what is basically our current app state,
我们将开始传入基本上就是我们当前的应用程序状态
or at least the variables that make sense.
或者至少是有意义的变量
And this is a common paradigm in web development with React as well.
这也是使用Reaction进行Web开发的常见范例
But basically, everything that we need to be preserve state to state,
但基本上 我们需要的一切都是州与州之间的保存
rather than just keeping global variables,
与其只保留全局变量
let's pass them between the states because the state machine allows
让我们在状态之间传递它们 因为状态机允许
us to do that in the change function.
我们需要在Change函数中执行此操作
And then whatever that state is in it's enter function,
然后不管它的Enter函数处于什么状态
it'll have access to that and it can just
它将可以访问它 并且它可以
set those values to self dot whatever and use them.
将这些值设置为Self Dot Anywhere并使用它们
But we no longer have global variables.
但我们不再有全球变量
We're just saying, here.
我们只是想说 给你
Here's the values that are important for you to continue on.
以下是对你继续下去很重要的价值观
And then that state will take its values and go to the next state
然后 该状态将采用其值并进入下一状态
and say, oh, OK, here are the values that you need to function.
然后说 哦 好的 这是你运作所需要的价值观
Like the serve, play, and all those states
比如发球 打球 以及所有这些状态
that have the core game play involved will probably
有核心游戏参与的人可能会
need to maintain a reference to like the paddle,
需要保持一个像桨一样的引用
and to the score, the amount of health we have.
更重要的是 我们所拥有的健康程度
But when we get to the end, for example, and then we no longer really
但当我们走到最后 例如 然后我们不再真的
need a paddle, we no longer really need bricks or anything like that,
需要一把桨 我们不再真的需要砖头或类似的东西
we just need to know what our high score is so that we can enter it
我们只需要知道我们的最高分是多少 这样我们就可以进入它
into our high score list, all we really need
进入我们的高分名单 我们真正需要的
to do is just pass in the high score state entry or just our high score,
要做的就是通过高分州进入或只通过我们的高分
and that's it.
就是这样
So it encapsulates all of our data.
所以它封装了我们所有的数据
And at a glance, we can sort of see what we need to pass between the states
一眼就能看出我们需要在两个州之间传递什么
and what's going to be relevant at a glance as well.
以及哪些内容也将一目了然
It just clean things up quite a bit.
它只是清理了相当多的东西
So that's what we're doing now on line 35.
这就是我们现在在第35行所做的
And henceforth, we will do this in every state as we see,
从今以后 我们将在我们所看到的每个州都这样做
but I'm going to sort of glaze over it in the future.
但我打算在未来对它进行某种程度的掩盖
We have a ServeState now.
我们现在有了一个ServeState
So a ServeState, this is very identical to what we did in Pong.
因此 作为一个ServeState 这与我们在Pong所做的非常相同
So we just wait for the user to press Space.
因此 我们只需等待用户按空格键
They can move around and then when they do press Enter,
他们可以四处走动 然后当他们按下Enter键时
basically the ball starts moving.
基本上 球开始移动了
And then we change the PlayState here using
然后我们使用以下命令更改此处的PlayState
the current values that are necessary.
所需的当前值
Paddle, bricks, health, score, and ball.
划桨、砖块、健康、得分和球
Those are basically the fundamental variables
这些基本上是基本的变量
that we need in order to keep track of our GameState.
我们需要它来跟踪我们的游戏状态
So we have a ServeState, it will wait for us to press Enter.
所以我们有一个ServeState 它将等待我们按Enter键
And then our main.lua, we have a new hearts table.
然后是我们的主路 我们有了一个新的心心桌
And then on line 208, because we're going
然后在208线上 因为我们要去
to need the ability to render health and render our score across several states,
需要在几个州呈现健康和分数的能力
Play, Serve, Victory, Game Over--
比赛、发球、胜利、游戏结束--
actually not Game Over, but the three before that.
其实不是游戏结束 而是之前的三场比赛
We don't want to duplicate those behaviors,
我们不想重复这些行为
so I'm just calling a function called Render Health, which
所以我只调用了一个名为Render Health的函数 它
just takes in whatever health is and then
只是吸收任何健康的东西 然后
we just set an X to virtual width minus 100.
我们只需将X设置为虚拟宽度减去100
And then for however many health we have, draw a heart
然后 为了我们的健康 画一颗心
from the hearts sprite sheet, which I separated the hearts out
从红心精灵纸上 我把心分开
into a smaller image so you can just split them on like eight by eight
分成更小的图像 这样你就可以把它们分成8乘8的
or whatever it is.
或者什么都行
But just draw those and then add 11 to X,
但只要把它们画出来 然后把11加到X上
and just keep going until we've drawn out however many hearts we have.
继续前进 直到我们拔出我们有多少颗心
That will draw full hearts.
这将吸引满满的心
And then three minus health will give us however many health we're missing.
然后 三减健康将会给我们带来多少我们错过的健康
So if we took a point of damage, this is going to be equal to one.
所以如果我们取一个损伤点 这将等于1
So then it'll draw one empty heart after that or it'll draw two empty hearts.
然后它会画出一颗空的心 否则它会画出两颗空的心
So draw however many full hearts we have, then draw the empty hearts.
所以 画出我们有多少颗饱满的心 然后画出空虚的心
And those are two separate sprites that we get from the image.
这是我们从图像中得到的两个独立的精灵
And that will have the effect of drawing our health.
这将对我们的健康产生影响
And then our score is simply, it takes a score variable that we pass into here.
然后我们的分数很简单 它接受一个分数变量 我们在这里传递
And also note that the render health [INAUDIBLE]
还请注意 渲染运行状况[INAUDIBLE]
and health variable and pass into it here.
和健康变量 并在这里传递给它
And so in our PlayState, we are calling both of these functions on line 135.
因此 在我们的PlayState中 我们在第135行调用这两个函数
Well, on line 135, we are calculating whether we
好的 在第135行 我们正在计算我们是否
go below the edge of the screen, which is another important part of the game.
走到屏幕边缘下方 这是游戏的另一个重要部分
Obviously, we need to detect when we've lost health.
显然 我们需要发现我们何时失去了健康
So it's as simple as this.
所以事情就是这么简单
If it's greater than the virtual height, decrement health by one.
如果它大于实际身高 健康就会减少1
If it's equal to zero, change to Game Over.
如果它等于零 则更改为游戏结束
Else change to the ServeState.
否则 更改为ServeState
And note that we're passing in all these variables to and from our states.
请注意 我们将所有这些变量传入和传出我们的州
The ones that are important.
那些重要的东西
Game Over just needs score, but Serve needs whatever
比赛结束只需要得分 但发球需要任何东西
variables we were already using.
我们已经在使用的变量
And then down here we're calling render score and render health,
然后我们在这里调用Render Score和Render Health
and then the GameOverState is simply--
然后 GameOverState就是简单的--
because it takes in score from the parameters list,
因为它接受参数列表中的分数
just wait for keyboard input to go back to the start and then render game over,
只需等待键盘输入返回到开始 然后渲染游戏结束
here's your score.
这是你的分数
It's self.score, and then that's it.
这是自己的得分 然后就是这样
Very simple.
非常简单
Very simple state.
非常简单的状态
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Sure.
科尔顿·奥格登：当然可以
COLTON OGDEN: The question was, do any of these states
科尔顿·奥格登：问题是 这些州中有哪一个
have access to their parent file?
有权访问他们的父文件吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Is everything in main.lua global functions?
科尔顿·奥格登：一切正常吗？Lua全球运行吗？
Yes.
是
Functions that you declare.
您声明的函数
Anything that's basically not specified as local that you define in main.lua
在main.lua中定义的基本上未指定为本地的任何内容
will be accessible anywhere in your application, including functions.
将可在应用程序中的任何位置访问 包括函数
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: You don't have to-- the question was,
科尔顿·奥格登：你不必--问题是
do you have to declare as public?
你必须申报为公共物品吗？
No, there is no notion of public.
不 没有公开的概念
In lua, anything that does not have a local specifier
在LUA中 任何没有局部说明符的东西
is assumed global, even if it's in a nested scope.
被假定为全局的 即使它在嵌套作用域中
So you could have a for loop, you could have several nested for loops
所以你可以有一个for循环 你可以有几个嵌套的for循环
and declare some variable without local, that variable can be accessed anywhere
并声明一些不带局部变量的变量 该变量可以在任何地方访问
above it or outside of it.
在它上面或外面
So it's pretty important to use local variables
所以使用局部变量非常重要
when you're not explicitly allocating something as global
当你没有显式地分配全局变量时
just to avoid the bug of for nested loops
只是为了避免for嵌套循环的错误
and you have some variable name like hello and you use it somewhere else.
你有一个变量名 比如hello 你可以在其他地方使用它
Good questions though.
好问题
So yeah.
所以是的
We have a bunch of states now.
我们现在有很多州
We have a GameOverState, a PlayState, we're
我们有一个GameOverState 一个PlayState 我们
rendering our score, rendering our health.
渲染我们的分数渲染我们的健康
If we go and take a look at Breakout5--
如果我们去看看Breakout 5--
is it a different window?
是另一扇窗吗？
There we go.
好了
We can see hearts at the top.
我们可以在顶部看到心脏
Score zero.
零分
Oh, and I forgot to mention the part where we actually add score now.
哦 我忘了说我们现在要加分了
So the bricks themselves in their on hit, or I should say in the PlayState,
所以砖块本身在击中时 或者我应该说在PlayState中
on line 81 when we detect a hit, we're just adding 10 to the score for now.
在第81行 当我们检测到一个命中时 我们现在只是在分数上加10
But later on, we'll do a calculation where
但稍后我们会做一个计算
we take tier and color into consideration
我们会考虑层次和颜色
and then perform arithmetic on that to get our total score for each ball hit.
然后进行算术运算 得出每次击球的总得分
But yeah, we have our health, we have our score.
但是 是的 我们有我们的健康 我们有我们的分数
And then once we take enough damage, we'll
一旦我们受到足够的伤害
end up going to the Game Over screen.
最终进入游戏结束屏幕
The Game Over screen will go back to our Start screen.
游戏结束屏幕将返回到开始屏幕
So making progress.
所以有进步
And then probably my favorite of the updates
然后可能是我最喜欢的更新
before we take a short break is the pretty colors update.
在我们短暂休息之前是美丽的颜色更新
So what this does is clearly we can have--
所以很明显我们可以
we've updated our level maker.
我们已经更新了水平仪
So rather than just having a bunch of very static bricks,
所以我们不需要一堆静止的砖块
we end up doing a little bit more complicated procedural generation.
我们最终做了一个更复杂的过程生成
It's not complicated though.
但这并不复杂
Just in levelmaker.lua in Breakout6, we have a few different constants here.
在Breakout 6的levelmaker.lua中 我们有几个不同的常量
So solid, alternate, skip, or none.
所以固体 交替 跳过 或没有
Actually, I don't think I use skip or none.
实际上 我不认为我用了跳过或没有
Just solid or alternate basically.
基本上是固定的或者交替的
We have flags now.
我们现在有旗子了
So number of columns.
列的数量
And we ensure that it's odd because even columns with generating patterns
我们确保它是奇数的 因为偶数列具有生成模式
leads to asymmetry.
会导致不对称
So make sure the number of columns is odd.
因此 请确保列数为奇数
Generate the highest tier and the highest color based on our level.
根据我们的级别生成最高级别和最高颜色
So in this case, we'll go no higher of a tier
所以在这种情况下 我们不会再往上走一层
than three because we have no higher tiers than three.
因为我们没有比三级更高的级别
It goes zero, one, two, three.
0 1 2 3
And then whatever our level divided by five is,
然后 无论我们的水平除以5是多少
and it would just take math.floor.
而且它只需要数学 地板
Math.floor takes in basically performing division and then truncating
Math.Floor基本上执行除法 然后截断
the decimal point.
小数点
Well, not division.
嗯 不是组织
It just literally truncates the decimal point off of a number.
它只是从字面上截断了一个数字的小数点
So a level divided by five.
所以这个水平除以5
Whatever that is before the decimal point.
不管小数点前的数字是多少
Level modular five plus three for the highest color.
级别模块五加三为最高颜色
So we'll cycle.
所以我们要骑车了
We'll go over and over again.
我们会一遍又一遍地复习
Go highest color one, two, three, four, five, and then we'll go to a new tier
走最高的颜色一 二 三 四 五 然后我们将进入一个新的层次
with level divided by 5.
级别除以5
So basically, every five levels will increment in tier,
所以基本上 每五个级别就会在层中递增
and then we'll start back at blue.
然后我们再从蓝色开始
And then we go on, and on, and on like that for every number of rows.
然后我们继续 继续 就像这样 每隔几行
So basically I have a few--
所以基本上我有几个--
I'm going to sort of glaze over this a little bit
我将在这一点上稍加强调
just because we're probably going to run short on time.
就因为我们可能会赶不上时间
But we have basically two flags.
但我们基本上有两面旗帜
Whether we're skipping bricks in this row or alternating bricks color wise.
无论我们是跳过这一排的砖块 还是按颜色交替使用砖块
And if we do, we need to set a color for it and a tier.
如果我们这样做 我们需要为它设置一个颜色和一个层
And then we basically just say, you know,
然后我们基本上只是说 你知道的
the same sort of logic that we had before we generated random rows
与我们在生成随机行之前使用的逻辑相同
and columns, but if we have the alternate flag on,
和列 但是如果我们打开了Alternate标志
then as we can see in some of these photos here, here we have skip is true.
然后 正如我们在这里的一些照片中看到的 我们在这里有一个跳跃是真的
So the color for that row is set to the blue, but skip is true,
因此 该行的颜色设置为蓝色 但跳过为真
so every other brick is just going to skip that iteration of the loop.
因此 每隔一块砖就会跳过循环的迭代
Same thing here, only it's offset by one.
这里也是一样 只是被1抵消了
Same thing here.
这里也是一样
So this is kind of a nice little pattern.
所以这是一种不错的小图案
And in each of these cases--
在每一种情况下--
actually not each of these cases.
实际上 并不是每一个案例都是如此
Notice this third one, it also set alternate to true.
请注意第三个参数 它还将Alternate设置为True
So it goes green, purple, green, purple, green, purple.
所以它变成了绿色 紫色 绿色 紫色 绿色 紫色
And so the logic there is if alternate is true, then
所以逻辑是 如果Alternate为真 那么
just flip the color every iteration.
只需在每次迭代中翻转颜色即可
If skip is true, don't generate a brick every other iteration, and so on
如果跳过为真 则不要每隔一次迭代生成一块积木 依此类推
and so forth.
以此类推
And then if you have solid or if you don't have alternate equals true,
如果有Solid 或者没有Alternate Equals True
then you have a solid brick like these blue ones.
然后你就会有一块坚固的砖 就像这些蓝色的
And if you have alternate but no skip, you get this sort of pattern
如果你有替代但没有跳过 你就会得到这种模式
where you have green, purple, green, purple.
有绿色、紫色、绿色、紫色
You know, any random color.
你知道 任何随机的颜色
And then also the number of columns is random.
而且列数也是随机的
So it can go--
所以它可以--
here we have 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11 but on this very bottom one,
这里有1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 但在最下面的这个上
we have that minus two it looks like because it can only go that wide.
看起来是负二 因为它只能这么宽
And in those here too.
这里的那些也是如此
Smaller size.
尺寸要小一些
That one there's no spacing.
那个没有空格
So these are very simple concepts.
所以这些都是非常简单的概念
Like should we skip a block this iteration?
比如 我们应该在这次迭代中跳过一个块吗？
Should we alternate the colors?
我们应该换一下颜色吗？
And when you put them all together, it produces
当你把它们放在一起时 就会产生
things that look as if they were almost handcrafted.
看起来像是几乎是手工制作的东西
Like this could be made by somebody.
就像这可能是某人做的一样
Like, that looks like it was made by somebody.
就像 这看起来像是有人做的
Pretty much every iteration of this.
几乎每一次迭代
I mean, even that, that looks like a shape almost.
我的意思是 即使是这样 那看起来也几乎是一个形状
Its just very simple but the results are pretty awesome in my opinion.
这很简单 但在我看来 结果非常棒
And so that's just the gist behind what we're doing.
这就是我们正在做的事情背后的主旨
We're just setting flags and just saying, you know,
我们只是在设置旗帜 然后说 你知道的
if we're skipping this turn and just every iteration,
如果我们跳过这一轮 跳过每一次迭代
every time we lay out a brick and we spawn a new brick on this row,
每次我们铺开一块砖 在这一排上生出一块新砖
just do or don't.
要么做要么不做
Just make it's color--
只要把它弄成彩色的就行了
pick two colors if we're alternating and then set
如果我们是交替的 选择两种颜色 然后设置
its color to whatever the off color is that we're alternating.
它的颜色是我们交替的任何关闭的颜色
And if we're skipping and alternating, then
如果我们跳过和交替 那么
we're just doing whenever we're on a brick that we're actually laying
我们只是在我们实际铺设的砖头上做
is when we change the color, the alternate color.
就是当我们改变颜色时 交替的颜色
And so like I said, I won't go into too much detail.
就像我说的 我不会讲太多细节
Happy to talk about the generator after class.
我很乐意在课后讨论发电机
But just because we're running short on time,
但我们时间不多了
sort of going to wave my hands over it.
我会在上面挥舞双手
But that's it in a nutshell.
但简单来说就是这样
So any questions before we take a break for five minutes?
在我们休息五分钟之前还有问题吗？
Yes?
- 是吗-是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: The question is, in an instance with this programming
科尔顿·奥格登：问题是 在这种编程的情况下
if the ball were so fast that it we're actually inside the brick,
如果球的速度快到我们实际上在砖块里面
would it what?
会怎样？
AUDIENCE: Would it still bounce back?
记者：还会反弹吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Would it still bounce back?
科尔顿·奥格登：它还会反弹吗？
The answer is no, it wouldn't.
答案是不 不会
This implementation doesn't take into consideration velocity
此实现不考虑速度
that goes too fast.
太快了
Mainly to-- for two reasons.
主要有两个原因
One, it's non-trivial to implement, and two,
第一 它的实现是不平凡的 第二
it's an interesting thing to look at, and observe,
这是一件有趣的事情
and be conscious of as you go forward in implementing your own games.
并且在你实现自己的游戏时要有意识
The current code, if it gets clipped inside of the brick,
当前的代码 如果它被夹在砖块里
it will have no edges that are peaking outside of the brick
它的边缘不会突出到砖的外面
and therefore, it will default to the final condition, which
因此 它将默认为最终条件
is the last else clause, which puts it below the brick.
是最后一个else子句 它把它放在砖块下面
So it'll just go below the brick.
所以它只会在砖下面
It'll almost be as if it came in from the underside and bounced out.
就像是从下面弹出来的
But like I alluded to earlier, if you want to implement something
但是就像我之前提到的 如果你想实现一些东西
like this yourself, you would have to slice up frame X and frame X plus one
像这样 你需要把X帧和X +1帧分割开来
into the size of the ball if the delta is so wide
如果三角洲很宽
that it either goes inside of a brick or it goes outside of a brick,
它要么在砖里面要么在砖外面
or if it skips a brick.
还是漏了一块砖
And this sort of solves that problem.
这个解决了这个问题
It solves both of those problems, but it's a little more
它解决了这两个问题 但它有点多
than we can cover in this example.
比我们在这个例子中所能涵盖的要多
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好吧
Let's take five and get back to it.
休息五分钟继续工作
And we're back.
我们回来了
So the next step is we have basically a layout dynamically
下一步就是我们有一个动态的布局
generated of interesting bricks now, but we haven't really
现在产生了许多有趣的砖 但我们还没有真正
implemented scoring any of these.
实施了对其中任何一项的评分
We just have score gets score plus 10, which
我们只有分数加10 这就是
isn't really particularly interesting.
其实并不是特别有趣
So Breakout7 is what I call the tier update, which
因此 Breakout 7就是我所说的层更新 即
should allow us to hit blocks that are a higher tier than just base blue.
应该允许我们命中比基本蓝色更高级别的块
And if they are of a higher color than base blue, they should go down a color.
如果它们的颜色高于基蓝 它们应该降到更低的颜色
So the hierarchy was, if we look back, blue
因此 如果我们回头看 这个等级是蓝色的
goes to green goes to red goes to purple goes to gold.
变成绿色 变成红色 变成紫色 变成金色
And if something is a higher tier, it goes
如果某个东西是更高的层次 它就会
to the next color below it but at that same tier,
到它下面的下一个颜色 但在同一层
unless it happens to be like blue and gray, in which case
除非它恰好是蓝色和灰色的 在这种情况下
it'll go back to blue.
它会变回蓝色
So how might we implement scoring based on this system?
那么 我们如何在这个系统的基础上实施评分呢？
What do we need?
我们需要什么？
What pieces do we need?
我们需要些什么呢？
What pieces do we already have that we can use to make this happen?
我们已经拥有了哪些我们可以用来实现这一点的东西？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: I'm sorry?
科尔顿·奥格登：什么？
COLTON OGDEN: So the answer was the brick index.
科尔顿·奥格登：所以答案是砖块指数
So yes, the brick skin and color are the pieces.
所以 是的 砖皮和颜色就是碎片
Yes.
是
So those are fields of brick.
所以这些都是砖块砌成的田地
So if we open up--
所以如果我们敞开心扉
I'm going to go up to Breakout7.
我要去看《越狱7》
And I'm going to start probably deferring a lot of this code
我可能会开始推迟很多代码
to future reading.
敬未来的阅读
But in brick here, the tier and the color--
但这里的砖块 层数和颜色--
sorry, not skin, but skin is for the paddle.
对不起 不是皮 但皮是用来划桨的
But the brick has a tier and it has a color.
但这块砖有一层 它有一种颜色
And so we need to perform some arithmetic on that here.
所以我们需要在这里进行一些算术运算
And that's essentially what lines 44 through 58 is.
这基本上就是第44行到第58行的意思
So basically-- oh, I apologize.
所以基本上--哦 我道歉
That's not actually where the arithmetic is.
这实际上并不是算术上的问题
44, that does compute, but this is the bit of code
44 这是可以计算的 但这是一小段代码
that computes how we can actually go backwards if we make a collision.
这就计算了如果我们发生碰撞 我们实际上可以如何倒退
So if we collide with a brick and it's of a higher tier than one
所以如果我们撞上了一块砖 它的层级比一层高
and it's a higher color than blue, it should be brought back one step.
而且它是一种比蓝色更高的颜色 它应该被带回一个台阶
But if it happens to be blue, in which case self.color gets one
但如果它恰好是蓝色的 在这种情况下 self.COLOR会得到一个
because blue is one, then it should just be removed from play
因为蓝色是其中之一 那么就应该把它从比赛中剔除
just like we've done before.
就像我们以前做的那样
Only now, we're also taking in tier and color.
只是现在 我们也在考虑层次感和色彩
So we're decrementing tier based on what index we're at
因此 我们根据我们所处的索引递减层
and we're decrementing color.
而且我们的颜色也在减少
And then this actually gets used in our PlayState.
然后这实际上会在我们的PlayState中使用
If we go to line 81, which previously just
如果我们转到第81行 它之前刚刚
had self.score gets self.score plus one, there's a little bit of math here.
让自己得分 得分加一 这里有一点数学知识
It's very simple though.
不过 这很简单
Just brick.tier times 200.
就是砖头 200倍
So make the tiers worth 100.
因此 让这些层的价值达到100
Plus brick.color times 25.
再加上砖块 颜色乘以25
And so if tier is zero, if it's a base then we're
因此 如果层为零 如果它是基数 那么我们将
just not going to get that 200 bonus.
只是拿不到那200英镑的奖金
But the first tier, everything is going to be worth
但在第一层 一切都将是值得的
25 times whatever its color is.
25倍 不管它是什么颜色
So one, two, three, four, five.
一、二、三、四、五
And then add 200 plus the brick.color for when
然后再加上200加上砖块的颜色
we get to the next set of bricks.
我们到了下一组砖
And so the result of this is--
这样做的结果是--
I believe this is GUI Breakout7.
我相信这是《图形用户界面突破7》
And then if we hit a brick--
如果我们撞到了一块砖--
since this one is blue, it should disappear.
既然这个是蓝色的 它应该会消失
And we're playing a new sound as well.
我们也在播放一种新的声音
New, like, death sound just to make it clear.
新的 就像 死亡的声音只是为了清楚
But notice they change colors.
但请注意 它们会改变颜色
So that's all we're doing.
这就是我们要做的一切
We're just taking their tier or their color
我们只是想要他们的等级或颜色
and just performing a simple decrement on it.
只需对其执行一个简单的减量
Looping back.
往回循环
In the event that we go down a tier, we should loop back up
在我们下一层的情况下 我们应该循环返回
to the highest color of the lower tier.
到较低层的最高颜色
So I'll let you look at the code for that
所以我会让你们看看这方面的代码
if you want to sort of get a more low level understanding of it,
如果你想对它有一个更低层次的理解
but that's the sort of high level understanding.
但这是一种高层次的理解
The next big concept that I'd like to introduce you guys to
我想向你们介绍的下一个重要概念是
is a particle system.
是一个粒子系统
And so particle systems are fairly omnipresent in video games,
因此 粒子系统在视频游戏中相当普遍
I would say, because they make effects that
我会说 因为它们产生的效果
or otherwise difficult to do with simple sprite
或者很难用简单的精灵来做
editing achievable very easily and realistically.
编辑可以非常容易和现实地实现
Just like fire, for example.
例如 就像火一样
Things that are very organic, and flowy, and have a lot going on
非常有机的 流畅的 有很多东西在进行
are often better represented with particle systems
通常用粒子系统表示得更好
than they are with simple sprite animation.
而不是使用简单的精灵动画
So does anybody know how we might be able to--
有谁知道我们如何才能--
how a particle system might work underneath the hood?
粒子系统如何在引擎盖下工作？
I think I alluded to it previously.
我想我以前提到过这一点
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
So what he said was in order to make fire,
所以他说的是为了生火
for example, just spawn a bunch of particles
例如 只需产生一束粒子
close to the center of wherever your fire is spawning and then outside of it
靠近你的火种产生的中心 然后在它的外面
spawn fewer.
产卵较少
That is absolutely a way to get fire to work,
这绝对是一种让火发挥作用的方法
and also taking into consideration the travel of your particles.
同时也要考虑到粒子的移动
For example, you might spawn a ton of fire particles really densely,
例如 你可能会非常密集地产生一吨的火粒子
but then maybe they have some logic that makes them go upwards.
但或许他们有某种逻辑让他们往上走
Maybe they have a negative delta Y and then some sort of acceleration
也许它们有一个负的增量Y 然后是某种加速度
so they've sort of trail off.
因此 他们已经有了一些踪迹
And then maybe sort of how to get a more realistic fire
然后也许是如何获得更逼真的火
look, they travel sort of upwards and then fade away.
看 它们向上移动 然后逐渐消失
So the way fire works, sort of thinking of things
所以火的运作方式 某种程度上是在思考事物
in terms of particles like that, you can achieve a lot of effects.
就这样的粒子而言 你可以达到很多效果
How might we implement, like, smoke, for example?
例如 我们如何实现吸烟？
Same system.
同样的系统
So we could have maybe a timer in our particle effect,
所以我们可以在粒子效果中使用计时器
or even a transition because in particle systems,
甚至是一种转变 因为在粒子系统中
often you have the ability to transition colors between particles.
通常 您可以在粒子之间过渡颜色
Let's say you start off red, go to yellow,
比方说 你从红色开始 到黄色
and then maybe your particle system transitions to gray or brown.
然后 您的粒子系统可能会过渡到灰色或棕色
And then over time, your particles are going up, they're dissipating.
然后随着时间的推移 你的颗粒物会上升 它们会消散
And they're also turning dark, they're turning brown,
它们也变暗了 它们变成了棕色
it sort of gives you the illusion of fire.
它给你一种火的错觉
And we won't be doing anything necessarily as
我们不会做任何事情 因为
complex as this in our code here, but in Breakout8, we
在我们的代码中如此复杂 但在Breakout 8中 我们
will be using Love's sort of integrated particle system which is just
将使用Love的一种集成粒子系统 它只是
love.graphics.newparticlesystem.
Love.graph ics.newarticlessystem
And it takes in a texture because all particle systems need some sort
它接受纹理 因为所有粒子系统都需要某种
of texture as their foundation.
质地作为它们的基础
And then it needs the number of particles that it could maximally emit.
然后它需要它最大限度地释放出的粒子的数量
And so each individual particle system can emit up
因此每个单独的粒子系统都可以向上发射
to a certain instance of particles.
到粒子的某个实例
And in the number, and speed, and whatnot of all
在数量、速度和诸如此类的东西上
those particles is ultimately the determining factor
这些颗粒最终是决定因素
for how you can get an illusion.
你如何才能得到一个幻觉
Back to last week's lecture, illusions, like, it's not fire, it's not smoke,
回到上周的演讲 幻觉 就像 这不是火 不是烟
it's just a bunch of particles responding
它只是一群粒子在响应
with colors and acceleration and stuff.
用颜色和加速度之类的东西
But there's a lot of functions that particle system gives you in Love2D,
但在Love2D中 粒子系统为您提供了很多功能
so I encourage you to look at that link just to explore some of them.
所以我鼓励你们看看这个链接 只是为了探索其中的一些
Love2d.org/wiki/particlesystem.
Love2d.org/wiki/articlessystem
We'll be using a few of them.
我们将使用其中的几个
Here I'm going to just briefly show you.
在这里 我将简要地向你们展示
So each individual brick when it gets hit
所以当每一块砖被击中时
is going to need a particle system of its own.
需要一个自己的粒子系统
Because our goal is--
因为我们的目标是--
I'll run the code for you so you can see it.
我将为您运行代码 这样您就可以看到它
So if you go to Breakout8 and then you run it,
因此 如果你转到Breakout 8 然后你运行它
we have a little bit of particles you saw there at the very end.
我们有一点粒子 你们在最后看到的
The blue you were probably able to see a little bit better.
你可能看得更清楚一点的蓝色
And then one last time.
然后是最后一次
So it spawns a bunch of little particles.
所以它会产生一堆微小的粒子
So can anyone tell me how they think the particles are
所以有没有人能告诉我他们认为这些粒子
behaving sort of in a nutshell?
一言以蔽之？
What the logic is for the particles?
粒子的逻辑是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] slightly random.
观众：[听不见]稍微有点随意
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
Slightly random.
有点随机
And if you look at it, you'll also notice that they tend to go downwards.
如果你看它 你也会注意到它们往往是向下的
So knowing that, we can probably just assume
所以知道了这一点 我们大概可以假设
that they have an acceleration that tends towards positive Y.
它们有一个趋向于正Y的加速度
And that's essentially all we really need to do.
这基本上就是我们真正需要做的事情
We spawn a bunch of particles outwards and then just set them--
我们向外产生一束粒子 然后把它们放在一起--
they have all a lifetime.
他们都有一辈子的时间
They last for a certain amount of time.
它们会持续一段时间
And then they fade between two colors.
然后它们会在两种颜色之间褪色
In this case, we fade from red to transparent or whatever color it is.
在这种情况下 我们从红色褪色为透明或其他任何颜色
And then after the lifetimes elapsed, it has the overall effect
然后在生命周期过去之后 它会产生整体的影响
of sort of this glimmering, gravity based effect,
这种闪烁的、基于重力的效果
but it's really just a bunch of particles that are
但它实际上只是一堆粒子
set to spawn in different directions.
设置为在不同方向产卵
Apologize for that.
为此道歉
So we'll take a look.
所以我们来看看
It's going to be in our brick class here in Breakout8.
它将出现在我们的《突破8》的砖块课上
So we're going to go to brick.
所以我们要去布里克
We have a bunch of colors that we're storing here.
我们在这里储存了一堆颜色
So if you notice, the particle systems adopt the color of whatever brick
所以如果你注意到了 粒子系统采用的是任何砖块的颜色
they're hitting just so that it stays sort of congruent
他们的打击只是为了让它保持一致
with what we're looking at.
与我们正在看的东西相吻合
So we're just storing a bunch of colors here.
所以我们只是在这里存储了一堆颜色
And I wouldn't worry too much about this.
我也不会太担心这一点
These are just colors from the sprite palette
这些只是精灵调色板中的颜色
that we used with our sprite art.
我们用在我们的精灵艺术上
There's specific colors that are only used in that sprite.
有一些特定的颜色只在那个精灵中使用
And having a palette, generally speaking,
一般来说 有一个调色板
allows your art to look a little bit more cohesive
让你的作品看起来更有凝聚力
when you're doing sprite art as opposed to just picking colors willy nilly.
当你在做精灵艺术 而不是任性地挑选颜色
If you say, oh, I'm going to only use 16 or 32 colors for this palette,
如果你说 哦 这个调色板我只会用16或32种颜色
you'll sort of have a more cohesive look and also
你会看起来更有凝聚力 而且
a very retro look because often hardware was
非常复古的外观 因为硬件通常是
limited to a certain amount of colors back in the day for older systems.
对于较旧的系统 仅限于一定数量的颜色
So it's nice to--
所以我很高兴--
as an aside-- and we'll look at it next week as well.
顺便说一句 我们下周也会讨论这个问题
Looking at when you're doing your own sprite art, try to use fewer colors
当你在做自己的精灵艺术时 试着使用更少的颜色
and then that will give you-- it also makes it easier for you.
然后这会给你--它也会让你更容易
You don't have to spend time choosing I want to have this shade of green.
你不必花时间来挑选 我想要这种绿色
I wonder if it looks good.
我想知道它看起来好不好
If you only have two shades of green or semi shades of green to choose from,
如果你只有两种深浅绿色或半深浅绿色可供选择
that's all you've got.
这就是你能做的一切
You have to make do with it what you can.
你必须尽你所能凑合着使用它
So what we're doing here is we're storing five colors from our palette.
所以我们在这里做的是从调色板中存储五种颜色
We're going to use this.
我们将利用这一点
And then when we trigger our--
然后当我们启动我们的.
so right here we're initializing a particle system.
就在这里 我们正在初始化一个粒子系统
So psystem gets love.graphics.newparticlesystem.
因此 psystem得到了love.graph ics.newarticlessystem
And then these are a few functions.
然后是几个函数
So feel free to look in the wiki for how these functions actually behave.
因此 您可以在维基中查看这些功能的实际运行方式
But lifetime acceleration and area spread
但终生加速和面积扩散
just are sort of the properties that influence
只是在某种程度上影响了
the way our particle systems behave.
我们的粒子系统的行为方式
And so using whatever our current color is,
所以使用我们当前的颜色
we're going to set our psystem's colors using setcolors function.
我们将使用setColors函数设置psystem的颜色
We're going to set it between two colors.
我们要把它设置在两种颜色之间
Color with 55 times tier alpha and color with zero alpha.
层Alpha的颜色为55倍 Alpha为零的颜色
So the higher the tier, the brighter the particles,
因此 层数越高 粒子越亮
but they'll always fade to zero alpha, if that makes sense.
但如果这有道理的话 它们总是会逐渐消失到零阿尔法
And then we'll just emit 64.
然后我们就会排放64
And this is all in the hit function.
这些都在HIT功能中
So all we've basically done is just add this particle system trigger in our hit
所以我们基本上所做的就是在我们的命中中添加这个粒子系统触发器
function, and it has the result of the behavior that we saw earlier.
函数 它具有我们前面看到的行为的结果
So any questions on particle systems or how we use them?
那么 关于粒子系统或我们如何使用它们有什么问题吗？
So level 9 is the progression update.
因此 级别9是进度更新
So the purpose of this update is to allow us to go from level one
因此 此更新的目的是让我们从第一个级别开始
to two to three to four and start get more interesting level
从两个到三个到四个 开始变得更有趣
generation that way.
一代人都是这样的
The gist of this is in our--
这件事的主旨在于我们--
so if you look at our StartState--
所以如果你看看我们的StartState--
so all we need to really do to store a level is just to store a number.
所以我们真正需要做的就是存储一个级别 只需存储一个数字
And then where do we increment the number?
然后我们在哪里递增这个数字？
Or when do we increment the number I should say?
或者我们什么时候增加我应该说的数字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
So we increment the level.
因此 我们增加了级别
We go to the next level when all of the bricks
我们进入下一阶段 当所有的砖块
are in play have gotten there in play flag set to false.
正在进行中已到达那里 正在进行中标志设置为假
So we have no pricks that are in play effectively.
所以我们没有有效发挥作用的刺头
So in our StartState--
所以在我们的StartState中--
so let's go ahead and look at Breakout9.
让我们继续看《突破9》
So StartState.
所以 StartState
We're passing in level gets one here.
我们正在通过这里的一层
We're just going to start off.
我们只是要开始了
When we're going to StartState, we're just going to pass level equals one.
当我们要去StartState的时候 我们只需要通过等于1的级别
And then henceforth, anytime we do any state changes from play to serve
从今以后 任何时候我们从打球到发球的任何状态变化
and to victory, as we'll see, victory being our new,
而胜利 正如我们将看到的 胜利是我们的新的
oh, you cleared this level.
哦 你清除了这个级别
Here's the next level.
这是下一个关口
We're just going to pass the level between them.
我们只是要超过他们之间的水平
And then in PlayState, the important bit of code here is on line 204.
然后在PlayState中 这里的重要代码在204行
So this is just a function called checkVictory,
所以这只是一个名为check Vicary的函数
which is exactly as James said.
正如詹姆斯所说的那样
We're going to iterate over the entire table and just say if it's in play,
我们将遍历整个表 并只说它是否在运行
return false because we're not in victory
返回错误 因为我们没有取得胜利
if we have any bricks that are in play.
如果我们有任何砖块在发挥作用
But return true if we didn't meet that condition.
但如果我们不满足该条件 则返回TRUE
And so this is just a simple way for us to check whether or not
所以这只是一种简单的方式 让我们检查
we are in a victory.
我们取得了胜利
And so on line 88 of the same file in our PlayState,
因此 在我们的PlayState中同一文件的第88行
we're just checking to say, hey, if self.checkVictory after we do any brick
我们只是想说 嘿 如果我们做了任何砖头之后 自己检查胜利
hit--
命中--
because that's when we've just set a brick to in play is false--
因为在那个时候 我们刚刚设置的一块砖是错误的--
just check victory.
只要检查胜利就好
And if so, play a new sound like a happy sound
如果是这样的话 播放一个新的声音 就像一个快乐的声音
that we've done a victory, and then just pass everything
我们已经取得了胜利 然后就把一切都抛诸脑后了
into the new VictoryState that we have here.
进入我们这里拥有的新的维克托州
And the VictoryState is simply a sort of just a message state.
而VictoryState仅仅是一种消息状态
So all it does is just renders everything as before,
所以它所做的只是像以前一样渲染一切
but it just says your current level complete.
但它只是说你目前的水平已经完成了
Self.level complete.
自我.级别完成
And then press Enter to serve and it'll go back to the ServeState
然后按Enter键服务 它将返回到ServeState
as soon as that happens.
一旦发生这种情况
And then here is where the actual progression happens.
然后 这就是实际进展发生的地方
When we go to the ServeState, we have our level but we want to add one to it.
当我们转到ServeState时 我们有自己的级别 但我们想要添加一个
So all we need to do when we trigger a transition into our next state, just
因此 当我们触发到下一个状态的转换时 我们需要做的就是
increment level by one here, and also create
在这里将级别递增1 并创建
a new map because bricks needs to get restarted because we have a new level.
一个新的地图 因为砖块需要重新开始 因为我们有一个新的关卡
Self.level plus one.
自我 级别加一
And that'll have the effect of, oh, we've gone from level one to two
这将会产生 哦 我们已经从第一级到第二级的效果
to three to four et cetera when we go between PlayState to the VictoryState
当我们在PlayState和VictoryState之间穿梭时 会有三到四个人等等
back to the ServeState.
回到ServeState
So any questions on how any of this works?
那么 对这一切是如何运作的有什么问题吗？
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: Do you have to worry about garbage collection for any
观众：你需要担心垃圾回收吗？
of the bricks at all?
所有的砖块吗？
Or is that handled by the Love engine somehow?
或者这是由爱情引擎以某种方式处理的？
COLTON OGDEN: Garbage collection is handled by Love.
科尔顿·奥格登：垃圾收集是由Love处理的
Yes.
是
Yeah.
嗯
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
Because the question was, do you have to worry about garbage collection
因为问题是 你需要担心垃圾收集吗？
when we are sort of clearing away the bricks and adding new bricks?
当我们清理砖块并添加新砖的时候？
The self.bricks table, this table here, it's
砖桌 这张桌子 它是
getting assigned to a brand new table from levelmap.createmap.
被分配到一张全新的桌子上 这张桌子来自velmap.createmap
When there are no references to an existing table,
当不存在对现有表的引用时
lua's garbage collector will trigger at whatever
Lua的垃圾收集器将在任何地方触发
interval it's set to trigger and clear up all that for you dynamically.
它被设置为动态触发和清除所有这些
Just like the same way that Java works.
就像Java的工作方式一样
Almost identical.
几乎一模一样
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好的
So we have progression.
所以我们有进步
In the sake of speed, I won't demo.
为了速度 我不做演示
It also takes a while just because we have to clear an entire level then
这也需要一段时间 因为我们必须清除整个关卡
get to the next level.
更上一层楼
But that's how the behavior works.
但这就是这种行为的运作方式
The next sort of iteration of this is high scores.
这种情况的下一种迭代是高分
And I will test to make sure whether or not this is actually working.
我将进行测试 以确保这是否真的有效
I know I changed some stuff.
我知道我改变了一些东西
Yeah.
嗯
So high score.
这么高的分数
Let's debug for a second.
让我们调试一下
So HighScoreState line 38 in Breakout10.
因此 在Breakout 10中 HighScoreState第38行
So HighScoreState.
所以 HighScoreState
And then the issue was [INAUDIBLE] to index field high scores.
然后问题是[INAUDIBLE]索引领域的高分
A nil value.
零值
OK.
好的
So that means that--
所以这意味着--
I think I might know the issue, but it's because I
我想我可能知道问题所在 但这是因为我
transitioned to a new user that doesn't have a saved file active on this.
已转换为新用户 该新用户在此上没有活动的已保存文件
The way that will transition, therefore, into love.file system, which
因此 将过渡到love.file系统的方式 它
is Breakout10's main new thing that it introduces-- so writing files
它引入的主要新事物是《突破10》的S--所以写文件
to your file system is done [INAUDIBLE] with love.filesystem.
到您的文件系统的操作使用love.filessystem完成[INAUDIBLE]
And there's a few things.
有几件事
So Love automatically gives you a directory, a save directory
所以Love会自动给你一个目录 一个保存的目录
that's pretty much hard coded.
这几乎是硬编码
There are a few exceptions as to how to not use that directory,
关于如何不使用该目录 有几个例外
but it assumes that you're always using that directory.
但它假定您一直在使用该目录
And with very few exceptions will you always use that folder.
除了极少数例外 您将始终使用该文件夹
It's like app data local on Windows, and application support,
它就像Windows上的本地应用程序数据 以及应用程序支持
and the name of your application on Mac.
以及您在Mac上的应用程序的名称
But it's a subfolder that Love has read and write access to
但它是Love拥有读写权限的子文件夹
for files on your file system.
用于您的文件系统上的文件
You can check whether it exists with love.filesystem.exists at some path.
您可以检查它是否与love.filesystem.存在于某个路径中
You can write to that path with some data, that data being a string value.
您可以使用一些数据写入该路径 这些数据是字符串值
And then love.filesystem.lines is an iterator,
然后love.filesystem.line是一个迭代器
which will allow you to look over any of the data that's
这将允许您查看任何数据
in a file at a given location.
在给定位置的文件中
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
AUDIENCE: Does this work if you [INAUDIBLE]
观众：如果你[INAUDIBLE]
COLTON OGDEN: It should.
科尔顿·奥格登：应该是这样
We can pull that up now actually and see.
实际上 我们现在可以把它拉出来看看
Because I know on their Love2D--
因为我知道他们的2D爱情--
so file system.
因此 文件系统
So the question was he ported his--
所以问题是他把他的.
when you port your Love app to the iPhone,
当你将Love应用程序移植到iPhone上时
will it have the same sort of behavior if you're--
它会有同样的行为吗 如果你是--
on an iPhone, will it have the same sort of save directory behavior?
在iPhone上 它会有同样的保存目录行为吗？
And it looks like it's not officially on here.
而且看起来它还没有正式出现在这里
I know that there is an iOS port for Love2D,
我知道有一个用于Love2D的iOS端口
or the ability to send it to Love2D.
或者将其发送到Love2D的能力
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: I have to imagine yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：我想是的
It probably has some sort of--
它可能有某种--
I'm not entirely familiar with how iOS handles sort of local storage,
我并不完全熟悉iOS是如何处理本地存储的
but I'm assuming that just in the way that it's been abstracted for desktops
但我假设只是从桌面抽象出来的方式
and for Android, it's also abstracted for iOS.
而对于Android 它也是为iOS抽象的
Haven't tested it myself.
我自己还没有测试过
I would experiment and see actually maybe with this code.
我会用这段代码做实验 看看有没有可能
See if you can maybe get it working with persistent high scores.
看看你能不能让它在持续的高分下发挥作用
I know that iOS does typically let you store a small amount of data per app
我知道iOS通常允许您在每个应用程序中存储少量数据
in some location, a fixed location, but I'm not
在某个地方 一个固定的地方 但我不是
entirely sure what that is offhand.
完全确定这是即兴的事情
I can look into it more and come up with a--
我可以更深入地研究一下 然后想出一个--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
I mean, not from firsthand because I don't have an Android,
我的意思是 不是来自第一手 因为我没有机器人
but it has official Android support.
但它有官方的Android支持
So I'm guessing it does, but I haven't tested it.
所以我猜是的 但我还没测试过
I have not tested it manually on Android to verify that.
我还没有在Android上手动测试它来验证这一点
But yes.
不过 是的
I believe-- because in the prior directory we were looking at when it
我相信--因为在之前的目录中 当它
showed--
展示了--
oh, it's actually up here.
哦 实际上就在这上面
This path here.
这条路在这里
This data/user/0/love2d.android.
这个数据/user/0/love2d.android
file save.
文件保存
That looks to me like it's the official sort of path
在我看来 这是一条官方的道路
that data is stored on an Android device for application.
这些数据存储在Android设备上 供应用程序使用
So I haven't tested it myself.
所以我还没有亲自测试过
But if you have an Android and you're curious or maybe an emulator,
但如果你有一个机器人 你很好奇 或者可能是一个仿真器
give it a shot and see if it works.
试一试 看看它是否奏效
Oh, and it even says here, there are various save locations.
哦 这里甚至写着 有各种各样的保存地点
And if they don't work, you can see what the actual location
如果它们不起作用 你可以看到实际位置
is with this function here.
就是这里的这个功能
The love.filesystem.get save directory.
Love.filesystem.get保存目录
That may work on iOS as well, so I'd be curious to hear about
这可能也适用于iOS 所以我很想知道
whether that actually works on that.
这是否真的能解决这个问题
Yeah.
嗯
So that's the gist.
这就是要点所在
Using the love.filesystem abstraction lets us read and write files.
通过使用love.filessystem抽象 我们可以读写文件
We can then just paste or we can just save whatever data
然后我们可以直接粘贴 也可以直接保存任何数据
we want anywhere within that directory.
我们想要那个目录中的任何地方
We can just create files in there and then use those to store our,
我们可以在那里创建文件 然后使用这些文件来存储我们的
you know, sort of game worlds, or character profiles, or whatnot.
你知道 游戏世界 或者角色简介 或者诸如此类的东西
How would we maybe go about implementing sort of like a high score list?
我们将如何实施一份类似高分名单的计划？
So I'll look.
所以我会找的
There's a picture here.
这里有一张照片
So we have 10 scores.
所以我们有10分
We'll assume that's fixed.
我们就假设这个问题已经解决了
Each of the scores has a name, and then each of the scores has an actual score.
每个分数都有一个名称 然后每个分数都有一个实际分数
So all we really need to do is just store ultimately the names
所以我们真正需要做的就是最终存储这些名字
and then the scores.
然后是比分
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: So we'll use an array.
科尔顿·奥格登：所以我们将使用一个数组
Their response was we'll use an array as sorted by that score.
他们的回答是 我们将使用按该分数排序的数组
Yeah.
嗯
Essentially that's exactly it.
从本质上说 就是这样
We're just going to keep a score table and each table
我们只需要保留一个计分表 每个表
is going to have a sub table.
将会有一张小桌子
And each of those entries, one through ten,
这些条目中的每一个 从一到十
is going to have a name and a score.
将会有一个名字和一个分数
And then once we're done with our application,
然后 一旦我们完成了应用程序
we'll just use love.filesystem.write.
我们将只使用love.filesystem.write
We'll have to convert all of those into a string
我们必须将所有这些内容转换为一个字符串
because we can't just take a table and then spit that out into a file.
因为我们不能只拿一张桌子 然后把它吐到一个文件里
We have to actually make it into some form that we can save
我们必须把它变成某种我们可以拯救的形式
and then reload back in somehow.
然后以某种方式重新装填
What would be the most efficient way, do you think, or a way we can do this?
你认为什么是最有效的方式 或者我们可以做到这一点的一种方式？
Probably just a new line separated list.
可能只是一个新的以行分隔的列表
The way that I've done it in this application
我在这个应用程序中这样做的方式
is just names, and then new line, score, new line, name, new line, score.
就是名字 然后是新行、分数、新行、名字、新行、分数
10, so 20 rows.
10 也就是20排
And that gets the job done.
这就完成了工作
Assuming that you don't tamper with the file, then everything should work.
假设您没有篡改文件 那么一切都应该正常工作
And you can write additional code as well
您还可以编写其他代码
to say, oh, if there is a score that's all
说 哦 如果有分数 那就是全部
garbled, we don't have enough scores, then probably
乱码 我们没有足够的分数 那么很可能
should render it accordingly.
应该相应地呈现它
My code does something similar to this, but not entirely.
我的代码执行类似的操作 但不完全是这样
The relevant code-- and I'm going to sort of just glaze over it.
相关代码--我将对其进行简单介绍
If we're looking at-- this is Breakout11, right?
如果我们在看--这是突破口11 对吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Oh, no, this is Breakout10.
哦 不 这是《突破10》
So in Breakout10, we have to load all the high scores
所以在《突破10》中 我们必须加载所有的高分
in main.lua, which is here.
在Main.Lua中 它就在这里
So set identity to Breakout or create a folder called Breakout
因此将身份设置为Breakout或创建一个名为Breakout文件夹
that we can save and read files to and from.
我们可以在其中保存和读取文件
If it doesn't exist, then just create them.
如果它不存在 那么就创建它们
In this case, I'm just seeding CTO my initials.
在这种情况下 我只是输入CTO作为我的首字母
And then I times 1,000.
然后我乘以1000
So 10,000 down to 1,000.
所以从一万降到一千
Just very simple data.
只是非常简单的数据
Writing into a file called breakout.lst.
正在写入名为Breakout.lst的文件
It can be whatever you want.
它可以是你想要的任何东西
All we're doing is reading lines from the data, or from the file.
我们所做的只是从数据或文件中读取行
And then this is if it doesn't exist.
然后这是如果它不存在的话
And then if it does exist, then we're going to iterate over it
如果它确实存在 那么我们将对其进行迭代
with love.filesystem.line, which will take a file
使用love.filesystem.line 它将接受一个文件
and then just split it on new lines basically and give you
然后基本上把它分成新的行 然后给你
an iterator over all those lines.
所有这些行的迭代器
So it can just say, OK, if it's a name, which
所以它可以说 好的 如果它是一个名字 哪一个
means that if it's one or three or five or seven in the list,
也就是说 如果名单上有一个、三个、五个或七个
then set the name to--
然后将名称设置为--
and we're using string.sub just in case they
我们使用的是字符串.sub.以防他们
write some long name or some long name gets-- they can't do it
写一些长名字 或者写一些长名字--他们做不到
through our game, but if it gets written to the file as some long name,
通过我们的游戏 但如果它以某个长名称写入文件
it should get truncated to three characters
它应该被截断为三个字符
so we can display it appropriately.
这样我们就可以适当地展示它
And then otherwise if we're not on a name line,
否则 如果我们不是在名字线上
if we're on, like, an odd line or even line,
如果我们在一条奇数或偶数行上
we should consider that a score and just use to number.
我们应该认为这是一个分数 只使用数字
Because we're using string data and if we try to assign,
因为我们使用字符串数据 如果我们尝试赋值
do any sort of comparisons numerically on the string data,
对字符串数据进行任何类型的数字比较
which we will have to do to compare high scores,
我们将不得不这样做 以比较高分
it's not going to work because it's going to see that there's strings.
它不会起作用 因为它会看到有弦
So we use to number here.
所以我们在这里用数字
Just a simple Lua function.
只是一个简单的Lua函数
And then that's it.
然后就是这样
And then we just return scores.
然后我们只需返回分数
And then I'll sort out what's causing the issue,
然后我会找出问题的起因
and then push that to the repo ASAP.
然后尽快把它推到回购上
But that has the effect of us being able to actually load all of our high scores
但这样做的效果是 我们实际上能够加载我们所有的高分
and display them at the start of the game.
并在游戏开始时展示它们
It doesn't take care of being able to actually input our score.
它不需要考虑能够实际输入我们的分数
And so we can do this with Breakout11, which you can see if you run the repo.
因此 我们可以使用Breakout 11来实现这一点 如果运行回购 您可以看到这一点
And you can test just to assign your initial score to some value like 10,000
您可以通过测试将初始分数分配给某个值 例如10,000
or 20,000, and then just lose on purpose and you
或者20,000 然后故意输掉 而你
get a sense of how it actually works.
了解它的实际工作原理
But essentially, it's just arcade style.
但从本质上说 这只是一种街机风格
You know, you had only three characters you could input your name.
你知道吗 你只有三个字可以输入你的名字
So does anybody have any idea as to how we are sort of storing this,
那么 有谁知道我们是如何存储这些东西的
or can pitch an idea?
或者可以提出一个想法？
So we have three characters and we want to--
所以我们有三个角色 我们想--
ideally if we're, let's say I want to go to C on the first one.
理想情况下 如果我们是 假设我想在第一个数上转到C
Let's say I pressed up twice so I get to C. How is it going from A to C?
比方说 我按了两次 这样我就到了C 从A到C怎么样？
You could just say, you could just render
你可以只说 你可以只渲染
I want to render the character A, the character A, the character A,
我想要渲染角色A 角色A 角色A
but how is it going to know when you want to go to B, or C, or D.
但它怎么知道你什么时候想去B、C或D呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: The pitch was, you could create
科尔顿·奥格登：投球是 你可以创造
a table with all of the characters and iterate through it.
一个包含所有字符的表 并对其进行迭代
You absolutely could do that.
你绝对可以做到的
It's a little bit bulky.
它有一点笨重
That might be what--
这可能就是...
actually, that's probably not how arcade systems did it back in the day.
事实上 这可能不是街机系统当年的做法
Because the way that we're going to do it here in Breakout11 is I
因为在《越狱11》中我们要做的是
added a new state called EnterHighScoreState.
添加了一个名为EnterHighScoreState的新状态
And if you recall, CS50 teaches this.
如果你还记得的话 CS50教授了这一点
But all sort of characters at the end of the day are just numbers.
但归根结底 所有类型的字符都只是数字
ASCI.
ASCI
In this case, 65, if you recall, is capital A.
在这个例子中 如果你还记得的话 65是大写的A
So all we need to do is just draw out whatever that character
所以我们要做的就是画出那个角色
cast to a string is, or character.
转换为字符串是或字符
And we do that simply down here in the draw function.
我们在下面的DRAW函数中简单地完成这项工作
If we do string.char, at char is three.
如果我们做string.char at char就是3
All that has the effect of doing is just taking that number
所做的一切只会产生这样的效果
and then converting it to a character.
然后将其转换为字符
So all we need to do then is what?
那么我们所需要做的就是什么？
When we want to go from A to B, B to C, C to D.
当我们想要从A到B B到C C到D
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
But then what happens if we're at A and we want to go down?
但如果我们在A 我们想往下走 会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: We would.
科尔顿·奥格登：我们会的
So if we're at A, then if we press downward and we want to go to Z,
所以 如果我们在A 那么如果我们向下按 我们想要到Z
the logic is in here.
其中的逻辑就在这里
But one we've incremented our code, if it's greater than 90, which is Z,
但是我们增加了代码 如果它大于90 也就是Z
then we should set it back to 65.
那我们应该把它调回65
We'll loop back to A.
我们将循环回A
And same thing here.
这里也是一样的
If we press down and we're at A, we've got to go back up to Z,
如果我们按下 我们在A 我们必须回到Z
so we just set it to 90.
所以我们把它设为90
So simple loop back logic.
如此简单的环回逻辑
And we just draw it, we highlight.
我们只是把它画出来 我们突出显示
And then once we've done that, the user presses Enter.
一旦我们这样做了 用户就按Enter键
We transition to the HighScoreState, actually,
实际上 我们过渡到High ScoreState
because this state should only trigger if they entered a new high score.
因为只有当他们进入新的最高分时 这种状态才会触发
Which means that we need to check in the VictoryState, or not the VictoryState,
这意味着我们需要登记到VictoryState 或者不是VictoryState
but rather in the GameOverState whether or not
而是在GameOverState中 无论是否
their score is higher than any of the stores in some sort of,
他们的分数比任何一家商店都要高
quote unquote, global scores table.
引用不引用 全球分数表
And then how do we think we're passing the scores back and forth now?
然后我们认为我们现在是如何来回传递分数的呢？
Does anybody recall how we're keeping track of app state?
有人记得我们是如何跟踪应用程序状态的吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yep.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
In the change function.
在更改功能中
So all we need to do is keep track of-- load
所以我们要做的就是跟踪--加载
our high scores at the beginning of the game,
我们在比赛开始时的高分
pass them all the way down the line.
把它们一直传到最后
And then finally-- and we can also load them in our EnterHighScoreState,
最后--我们还可以将它们加载到EnterHighScoreState中
but we need to keep track of what our high scores are in the GameOverState
但我们需要跟踪我们在GameOverState中的高分是多少
so that we know, oh, I've got a high score.
这样我们就知道 哦 我得了高分
Let's instead of transitioning back to the StartState, let's transition
与其转换回StartState 不如让我们转换
to the EnterHighScoreState so the user can add their high score to the list.
添加到EnterHighScoreState 以便用户可以将他们的高分添加到列表中
And then once they've entered their high score, which is here,
然后一旦他们进入了他们的高分 也就是这里
we'll just write it to this file again.
我们只需将其再次写入此文件
Compile a score string, which takes name and score of our scores.
编译一个分数字符串 它接受我们的分数的名称和分数
We take whatever score that we were at that's--
我们拿我们当时的分数 那是--
we look through our scores table backwards
我们倒着看我们的分数表
and when we find a score that's lower than ours,
当我们找到比我们的分数低的分数时
we just keep track of that index until we get to one that's higher than ours.
我们只是跟踪这个指数 直到我们得到一个比我们的指数更高的指数
In which case the one plus one, that index plus one
在这种情况下 一加一 该指数加一
is what we should then overwrite.
是我们应该改写的内容
And so we shift all the other ones below accordingly.
因此 我们相应地将下面的所有其他部分移位
And we do that in this class if curious.
如果好奇的话 我们在这节课上也会这么做
And so I'm just going to breeze through the last couple.
所以我要轻松地看完最后一对选手
The paddle select update is just kind of a fluffy state
Ppale SELECT更新只是一种模糊状态
that lets us add a element of sort of, like, user selection to our game.
这让我们可以在我们的游戏中添加一些元素 比如用户选择
In our PaddleSelectState here, we transition immediately.
在我们的PaddleSelectState中 我们立即进行转换
Instead of going to the [INAUDIBLE] PlayState now,
而不是现在去[INAUDIBLE]PlayState
we're going to go from Start to Paddle Select when we hit Start Game.
当我们点击开始游戏时 我们将从开始到划桨选择
So we're going to go to--
所以我们要去...
and then the Paddle Select class itself.
然后是Paddle Select类本身
CurrentPaddle gets one, and then all it essentially
CurrentPaddle得到一个 然后它基本上
is is us drawing two arrows here.
我们在这里画两个箭头
And so if we're at number one-- in this case, I think we're at number three--
所以如果我们是第一名--在这个例子中 我想我们是第三名--
then both of these arrows will be completely opaque.
那么这两个箭头都将是完全不透明的
But if we're on the left or the right edge, they should darken to say to us,
但如果我们在左边或右边 他们应该变暗对我们说
oh, we can't move left or right anymore because we're
我们不能再左右移动了因为我们
at either index one or four or five, and there's only that many colors.
在索引1或4或5处 只有那么多颜色
And then render whatever that color variable
然后渲染这个颜色变量
is using the quads table that we had before of the different tables.
就是用我们之前用过的四元表
And then just instructions.
然后只是指令
And then from there is where we'll end up transitioning to the ServeState
然后从那里我们将最终过渡到ServeState
rather than going to the ServeState from the StartState.
而不是从StartState转到ServeState
And all the code in that is here.
所有的代码都在这里
We have sound effects playing.
我们在放音效
And then making sure that we also play a different sound
然后确保我们也播放不同的声音
effect based upon whether they're at the left or the right edge.
效果取决于它们是在左边还是右边
If they're on the left edge and they try to go left,
如果他们在左边想往左走
it should play like a sound that sort of sounds a little rougher
它应该像一个声音 听起来有点粗糙
to let them know that they can't go left,
让他们知道不能向左走
and the opposite for the right edge.
而右边缘则相反
And then once that's all done, once they press Enter on whatever paddle
一旦他们按下回车键
they want, they're going to get the paddle,
他们想要 他们会得到球拍
we're going to instantiate a paddle, pass that into the ServeState,
我们将实例化一个paddle 将其传递到ServeState
and we're going to take currentPaddle from the state, which
and we're going to take current当前Paddle桨from the state状态 which哪一个
is whatever value they got by scrolling between all the different paddles.
就是他们在不同的拨片之间滚动得到的值
And then the last update, which is my favorite part of most every lecture
然后是最后一个更新 这是几乎每堂课我最喜欢的部分
I think is the music update.
我想是音乐的更新
And all that really is is just music set play in main.lua,
而所有这一切实际上只是音乐集发挥在主要.lua
and then set looping to true, and then we have a game.
然后将循环设置为真 这样就有了一个博弈
And this is our Paddle Select.
这是我们的Paddle Select
So notice the arrows are semi-opaque on the left and the right.
请注意 左右两边的箭头是半透明的
It's kind of hard to hear, but when I press right now
听起来有点难 但当我现在按下
it's kind of like there's a bit of a rougher sound.
有点像是有一点粗糙的声音
We choose red.
我们选择红色
We go to level one and we transition to the ServeState
我们转到第一级 然后转换到ServeState
from the PaddleSelectState, and then we just play the game as normal.
PaddleSelectState 然后我们就像往常一样玩游戏
And that's basically all there is to it.
这基本上就是它的全部
And there is a couple of features we didn't have time to really go over
有几个功能我们没有时间去真正了解
like making sure we recover HP if a certain amount of points
比如确保我们在一定数量的点数
have been elapsed, but I encourage you to look
已经过去了 但我鼓励你去看看
into that when you trigger a hit.
当你触发一次命中的时候
There's some logic in the PlayState to say, oh,
在PlayState中有一些逻辑可以说 哦
if they've gone over a current recovery threshold,
如果他们已经超过了当前的复苏门槛
let's add one heart to the player, you know, just keep them playing.
让我们为球员增加一颗心 你知道的 让他们继续比赛
Just to reward them for their high score.
只是为了奖励他们的高分
Next time we'll cover a few concepts.
下一次我们将介绍一些概念
So basic shaders.
所以基本的着色器
Shaders are like little programs you can run in your graphics card
着色器就像可以在显卡上运行的小程序
and do fancy effects, but we won't go into too much detail.
并制作奇特的效果 但我们不会深入到太多细节
Anonymous functions.
匿名函数
We've seen a lot of anonymous functions in Lua in the context of Love.
我们在Lua中看到了很多关于Love的匿名函数
They're just functions without a name, and you can just
它们只是没有名称的函数 您可以
use them as function arguments and do all sorts of cool stuff with them.
将它们用作函数参数 并用它们做各种很酷的事情
We'll use them for callbacks next week when we do things
下周我们做事的时候 我们会用它们做回调
like tweening, which is taking some value
比如Twening 它正在获得一些价值
and making it interpolate over time to some other thing.
并让它随着时间的推移插入到其他东西中
Because right now we've basically just been updating things based on velocity,
因为现在我们基本上只是根据速度进行更新
but we haven't really done anything based on time.
但我们并没有真正按照时间来做任何事情
So we'll take a look at that in more detail
所以我们将更详细地了解这一点
next week with a library called timer, which is really fantastic.
下周将有一个名为Timer的图书馆 这真的很棒
Lets you time things and then chain things together.
允许您对事物进行计时 然后将事物链接在一起
We'll be covering the game Match Three if familiar.
如果熟悉的话 我们会报道第三场比赛
It's basically Candy Crush.
这基本上就是糖果粉碎传奇
We'll be using a different tile set, but it's the same idea.
我们将使用不同的瓷砖设置 但这是相同的想法
And we'll have to calculate how to actually find out
我们将不得不计算如何真正找出
whether we've gotten a match in the grid, our tile grid,
无论我们是否在网格中找到了匹配 我们的瓷砖网格
and then shift the blocks accordingly and do all the other logic, add score.
然后相应地移动这些块 然后做所有其他逻辑 加分数
And then basically since it's so fundamental to Candy Crush and games
然后基本上 因为它是糖果粉碎传奇和游戏的基础
of its nature, we will have to cover how to sort of generate
对于它的本质 我们将不得不讨论如何在某种程度上生成
these maps procedurally to have tiles that are laid out in a dynamic way,
这些地图在程序上具有动态布局的瓦片
and also in a way that doesn't start off with any matches
在某种程度上 也不是从任何火柴开始
because then that wouldn't make any sense because the matches have
因为那就没有任何意义了 因为比赛已经
to resolve.
来解决问题
And then we'll take a little time if we have the time next week
如果下周有时间的话我们会抽出一点时间
to talk about sprite art again and palettes.
再次谈论精灵艺术和调色板
And maybe I'll show you guys how to sort of convert images from one
也许我会向你们展示如何将图像从一个
palette to another in, like, a program that I use, Aseprite,
调色板到另一个 比如 我使用的一个程序 Aseprite
but you can do this in any sort of large photo editing software.
但你可以在任何类型的大型照片编辑软件中做到这一点
And then assignment two is a couple of extensions to Breakout.
第二项任务是《越狱》的几个扩展
So if you noticed in the sheet there were a few little sprites here
所以如果你注意到床单上有几个小精灵
at the bottom--
在底部--
so get rid of the quad outlines.
所以 去掉四边形轮廓吧
So these little things down here are, I'm assuming,
所以下面这些小东西 我猜
they're meant to be power ups.
它们应该是能量充沛的
They look like power ups.
它们看起来像是通电了
But the goal of the pset is to implement a power up.
但pset的目标是实现通电
And a power up is going to be such that when you grab it,
一旦启动 当你抓住它的时候
you'll get two additional balls, or however many you want actually,
你会得到两个额外的球 或者实际上你想要多少球
that will spawn in addition to your one and detect collisions on their own.
它将在你的那个之外产生 并自己检测碰撞
So you'll have several and they'll score points for you.
所以你会有几个 他们会为你得分
And, of course, only when the last ball comes below the surface of the screen
当然 只有当最后一个球落在屏幕表面以下时
should you trigger a Game Over.
你是否应该触发一场游戏结束
And then I want you to add-- and this will also
然后我想让你们加上--这也会
be more detailed than the spec-- but I would
比说明书更详细--但我会
like you to add growing and shrinking to the paddle.
喜欢你把成长和萎缩加到桨上
So currently, we have like four different sizes of paddle,
所以目前 我们有四种不同大小的球拍
but we're not using them.
但我们没有使用它们
So it would be nice if when we gain enough points or we lose points, or not
所以如果我们得到了足够的分数或我们失去了分数 那就好了
points, but lives rather, we increase or decrease the size of the paddle
分数 而不是生活 我们增加或减少桨的大小
accordingly just to introduce another level of challenge
因此 我们要引入另一个层面的挑战
and or lack of challenge.
或者缺乏挑战
And then finally, one last part which is in the sprite sheet as well,
最后 最后一部分也在精灵表中
there's a key block here and a key power up here.
这里有一个钥匙块 这里有一个钥匙电源
So sort of let the power up come, pick the power up with your paddle.
所以让力量来 用你的桨把力量捡起来
And then only when you have that power up should you
只有当你有了这种力量
be able to break the block with a key.
能用钥匙打破障碍
And you should take this into consideration
你应该考虑到这点
when generating your levels as well.
你也可以在生成水平时使用
So you'll have to also get your hands dirty with the level maker.
所以你也必须用水平仪弄脏你的手
But all in all, that was Breakout.
但总的来说 这就是突破
So I'll see you guys next time.
我们下次见
Thank you.
谢谢